Krish NAik: Alright guys, am I audible? Please let me know in the chat.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright, fine.
Krish NAik: So, today we'll be starting the graph rack part.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I think few people have joined. Let's wait for others.
Krish NAik: Perfect. So, the first step, okay, we'll be downloading Neo4j. How many of you have Neo4j in your,
Krish NAik: system already installed. Otherwise, I will just start sharing my screen, just wait.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: I'm sharing the link, everybody please do download.
Krish NAik: It has multiple editions, so simply, like, you can work according to your own operating system. So here you will be getting the download option, so I'm sharing this link. Please try to open it.
Krish NAik: So, in the chat… okay, where is the chat window?
Krish NAik: Just tweet.
Krish NAik: Even when I cannot say goodbye.
Krish NAik: I'll let everybody install. It will take, a little bit of time, but I think…
Krish NAik: Pretty much easy, like, if, because the main problem with a cloud cluster, you can only create one.
Krish NAik: That's why it's better to go ahead with the local one.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, the same thing, as you can see here, Neo4J, it has a cloud one, but in cloud, you can only create one instance. So, it's better, and it's called Neo4J Aura.
Krish NAik: Okay, so the cloud one, later on you guys can explore. The same thing, the same way that we'll be doing.
Krish NAik: Okay, so the only problem is only one instance that you can create it for free. The rest, like, in local, you can create any number of instances. So that is the best thing.
Krish NAik: Today's discussion is pretty much discussion simple. We have, I think, the notebook will have… Just quick.
Krish NAik: I'm sharing the Git also.
Krish NAik: You guys can take a clone.
Krish NAik: Yes, we are downloading and installing Neo4j, the same stuff that I have told right now, everybody, please do download.
Krish NAik: And do the installation.
Krish NAik: I think others are joining… Okay, a few people are… Left yet to join.
Krish NAik: Now, how many of you have worked with graph databases before?
Krish NAik: So, grab databases, when I say it's pretty much like it comes under NoSQL only.
Krish NAik: the NoSQL family. If you have not worked, here's the syntactically, it's a bit different, so that's why I even shared a markdown file, if you see here, so you guys can actually go through the particular syntax. I'll be showing you, like, step by step.
Krish NAik: How to do the execution, because here, no identity relationship, three things are very important.
Krish NAik: Because, teaching GraphDB is different, but here we'll be directly utilizing it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… but yes, I will give you that basic.
Krish NAik: Rahul Pereira worked with Dynamo… no, no, no, no. DynamoDB is different, Mongo is different. In AWS, Rahul, it's, Neptune is there.
Krish NAik: That is, proper Graph 1. Otherwise, Neovolge J.
Krish NAik: Because NeoForge is the most widely used one. Few other products in the last 2 years in the market, it's become very famous. One is Falker, the other one is…
Krish NAik: Surreal team.
Krish NAik: They got good funding.
Krish NAik: Everybody, please do download it, okay, and then let me know.
Krish NAik: Once the download part is done, you will see something like this, okay? So… pretty much a blank one.
Krish NAik: So… Quickly do it, and then, let me know.
Krish NAik: I think this is your right batch, alright.
Krish NAik: And I think Project 3 is done, so, for that, I'll be releasing the form today. Okay, so once you guys are ready, then I think I have created that form, so…
Krish NAik: Everybody, please do, like, fill out the form, I'll be sharing it, so I'm just waiting for others. Looks like 20 to 30 folks or less today, as compared to other sessions.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… then I think… Yes This one is the form.
Krish NAik: Bh.
Krish NAik: I don't know how many students are here right now? 100. Okay.
Krish NAik: Okay, again, less, but I'm sharing. In the meantime, just keep it bookmarked, you guys can fill it later. Right now, filling it up is not important. Okay, so as I told you, like,
Krish NAik: one AWS document that I have shared, so similarly, like, right now, like, three teams can be created, one for AWS, one for GCP, one for LGO.
Krish NAik: So right now, through this form, I'm just looking into the team members who are actually interested in the development part, and, like, 8 members and 2 leads, so in a team close to…
Krish NAik: Total 10 people, so 10, 10, 30.
Krish NAik: That's a rough estimation. I think within 2 months, you guys can do it, so I've taken a rough
Krish NAik: 8 weeks estimated time. Okay, so everybody, please do fill up, so once…
Krish NAik: the final things will be shortlisted by AK. Once you guys fill it up, I think by next week, I can let you know what is the final team formation.
Krish NAik: Alright, so please let me know the new 4G part is done, yes or no.
Krish NAik: I think it's simple.
Krish NAik: For everybody, the installation is done.
Krish NAik: And can you see a very similar type of UI?
Krish NAik: not yet still taking time. In Windows, is it taking time? Because I'm not sure, in Mac, it's pretty much straightforward, so…
Krish NAik: Mmm… form link. I think I have shared the form link already.
Krish NAik: It's a graph database.
Krish NAik: Moit Bisharia.
Krish NAik: new 4J graph database. We'll be talking about the graph right now?
Krish NAik: Just remember, for your simplicity, okay, so let me just stop sharing and start, looking into the notes.
Krish NAik: Because the idea is to make the reference much more easier, rather than making it much more complex. Okay, so just wait, let me start sharing my notes. Few things I'll be just writing, so that you guys can get a quick idea.
Krish NAik: you guys have to attach one more node. Okay, according to our main rep… till now, whatever the things that we have discussed.
Krish NAik: So, let me start sharing iPad via ear, please.
Krish NAik: Mmm, just wait.
Krish NAik: Oh, I think this is soap.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I think everybody can see my notes.
Krish NAik: So till now, in the rack, what are the things that we have discussed, okay?
Krish NAik: So let's… Looks like it is this child, or what.
Krish NAik: Okay, so in the meantime, let me just say, so, if I say hybrid rack, what is the first thing that comes in your mind?
Krish NAik: Quickly thing.
Krish NAik: Cheers, guys.
Krish NAik: What is the first thing that comes to your mind? Dense, sparse? Okay. Why re-ranking comes? R-ranking should not come in your mind.
Krish NAik: Okay, so by default… Okay, looks like my pencil is not charged, okay?
Krish NAik: So, fine, let me just open Zed, and I will write it in note.
Krish NAik: Third, just to… Hmm…
Krish NAik: Well, let me just, get the desktop crew…
Krish NAik: All right, so till now, I read.
Krish NAik: rack, whenever I'm saying, the first thing that comes to your mind is, like, a sparse Plus… dense.
Krish NAik: If you remember, there was another thing that can be attached. Can anybody tell me?
Krish NAik: Another thing that can be attached.
Krish NAik: With these two.
Krish NAik: not Heidi… RRF, again, doesn't matter. RRF, if you want to combine sparse and tens, then only. Yes, I was actually looking for multi-vector.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Now, generally, like, these three things can be attached. Now, with that, if you want to attach one more node, okay, now that becomes for the graph right.
Krish NAik: Okay. So, generally, like… Good luck.
Krish NAik: This will be the final goal.
Krish NAik: Now, we will start with simply, like, in every language chain in Llama Index, there will be a specific retriever, so a graph retriever will be there, so we'll be importing that. Before that, we need to create a knowledge base. With every graph.
Krish NAik: There will be a knowledge base which would be attached.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this knowledge-based creation, we will focus today, so exactly how it is being done. Again, this is done by using an LLM.
Krish NAik: Okay, but actually, in real world, if you are working in an organization, so it won't be through an LLM, because what type of data you have, you need to really understand the relationship, in your documents, what type of entities are coming.
Krish NAik: For now, we will be passing it directly, okay, through an LLM, and we… And decide that. But,
Krish NAik: Going forward, like, if you are working, there will be a certain standard in your documents, like, it cannot be, like, anything can come into the system.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why, if anything is coming, it becomes much… problematic to work with GraphRite.
Krish NAik: Like, the main problem with graph fraggers, like.
Krish NAik: When it becomes very, very big, it means your craft becomes very, very big.
Krish NAik: Scalability is one of the major issues.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's… if it is small, it's fine.
Krish NAik: But, again, like, if it is…
Krish NAik: growing very, very quickly, then again, it's not, an optimal solution.
Krish NAik: So that's why, like, GraphFrag, it's not, like, every time you'll be using, the fallback condition will come. So, that's why, like, these two things with GraphFrag, okay, so we'll be building a solution. So it's simply a node that we'll be attaching. So, we'll be talking about that step by step.
Krish NAik: This is the high-level intuition. Now, knowledge base, I'll be talking about exactly what will be the knowledge base, okay? And three important things with respect to the structure. One will be node, one will be entity, and one will be relationship, okay? I'll be showing you these things, but…
Krish NAik: This is the high-level intuition for now. Three things that we'll be building. Whenever we'll be working with any graph.
Krish NAik: databases, these three things can come. And the other things that come is properties.
Krish NAik: Based on which we can add any type of filtering mechanism.
Krish NAik: And, whenever you are working with graph databases, so what is the language? So generally, if I say SQL, if you are working with… so you say SQL,
Krish NAik: query language. So here, what is called?
Krish NAik: Anybody?
Krish NAik: It's called Cypher, okay? Not GraphQL. GraphQL is different. It's related to API stuff.
Krish NAik: That's… okay, so, yes.
Krish NAik: What about Langraph? Langgraph… no, no, no, Langraph is different.
Krish NAik: I'll be using Langrav today, I think, in one of the notebooks I have, but, let's start on, because the idea of using Langrav in the notebooks, if you really check, it is only used for routing.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, because if you have a stateful application using Langchain, you cannot create anything stateful. Everything will be stateless. So, that's why, just because of routing purpose, I have used Langdrop. Otherwise, there is no major use.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, right now, just focus on these things. So, GraphQL is totally different, and again, LangGraph is not an actual graph database, so never get confused.
Krish NAik: I will be coming to the use cases, don't worry, but first of all.
Krish NAik: Let's look into, the basics, at least, okay? So, I think I have shared one markdown file, so let's create one instance.
Krish NAik: Because at least you need to make it comparable with SQL, so exactly, like, how in SQL, what happens, how you create a node, so let's look into the basics. Then we will jump into the research paper.
Krish NAik: So, exactly, because in research paper, directly, they will be talking about the few problem statements, like graph rack, where it needs to be used, like financial services, social media, okay? They have given 4 to 5 major domains where it is helpful. It's not like in every domain.
Krish NAik: It's, really useful.
Krish NAik: Can you share the Markdown file? It is in the repo, I think.
Krish NAik: Yes or no, please let me know, because I feel that I have shared that, yes.
Krish NAik: Yes, newforgerbrowserGuide.md.
Krish NAik: Please have a look. This is the one.
Krish NAik: Is Knowledge Graph and GraphRaga Muhit?
Krish NAik: Whenever you are working with any type of graph databases, there you create a knowledge.
Krish NAik: Bill, first up.
Krish NAik: Okay, now that knowledge base is actually the knowledge graph.
Krish NAik: Alright, so everybody please do open the first, thing here. Okay, because we'll be creating a simple instance, and the idea is to look into a few of the basic commands, then I will come into the next step.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Let me see in the meantime, because I need to write in my notes, but… alright, looks like the plane is now charged.
Krish NAik: Just wait. So, I think… I can now start writing. Just wait… My bed laugh.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: So, first of all, GraphRAT, so you need any type of GraphDB.
Krish NAik: Okay, so graph database right now, when I'm telling.
Krish NAik: GRAPHDB. Some of the examples of GraphDB. So, right now, in, today we'll be talking about NeoVorch.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Then, you have Neptune, AWS, which is very famous. Similarly, in every cloud, there is one, then…
Krish NAik: Right now, for…
Krish NAik: LLM-based tasks, like FalcoDB, become very, very famous. It's built on top of C. Okay, so if anything is built on top of C, it is actually very, very fast, so… like, Falco is good, the other one is SurrealDB.
Krish NAik: This is also becoming much more famous, I can say. Okay, so out of this, we will start with Neo4j. Neo4j is the widely used one, okay? Now, GraphDB, when I say, so two types of databases we have. One is your RD,
Krish NAik: Okay, and the other one, if I say that anything that comes here, you can take, like, SQL, Postgres.
Krish NAik: Okay, most common ones. And then you have your NoSQL.
Krish NAik: Under NoSQL, what are the things that comes?
Krish NAik: Common example, like Mongo, I think everybody has used.
Krish NAik: Radius… Anybody has used Cassandra?
Krish NAik: Okay, so similarly, all of your grab-based operations that comes, it comes under NoSQL only. It's not like a third category it is treated as. Okay, so any type of grab-based thing that comes, it comes under NoSQL, so don't get, confused there.
Krish NAik: Cosmos, yes, Cosmos will come here.
Krish NAik: If you say Cosmos.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: So, the main GraphDB, okay, so any graph-based operations, it comes under NoSQL hold.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now, from here.
Krish NAik: So, let me try to… Create a few notes.
Krish NAik: Perfect.
Krish NAik: Now, let's take a simple example of node 1.
Krish NAik: Note 2.
Krish NAik: and node 3, okay? Now, simply, like, nodes, you can think about 3 different type of persons that I'm talking about. Okay, now, if you want to define some type of relationship.
Krish NAik: This one with this one. This one with this one.
Krish NAik: Okay, so similarly, this one with this one.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this is your R that I'll be defining, which is your relationship.
Krish NAik: Okay, so relationship 1, this is… will be your R2, this will be your R3.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is a high-level intuition, similarly, like, when I'll be writing the code. So, I'll be defining all this, okay? So, this is the node that I want to create. Okay, now, within the node, there will be properties.
Krish NAik: Okay, so every node will be having some type of properties. Based on those properties, you can apply filters.
Krish NAik: Okay, just like in SQL, you can do very similar type of operations that you can perform here. So, like, P1, P2, P3.
Krish NAik: Okay. Now, there can be similarities, like, few properties of one node can be similar to other node, or it might be different also, both the conditions.
Krish NAik: Okay, now we will try to build something like this. We will start with something very, very small, so I've already shared all the commands, now we will be looking into the commands. Okay, now let's start, first of all, by building a simple node, then another node, and then we will try to create a relationship.
Krish NAik: Okay? Because right now, just forget about RAG and everything else. Just look into, like, what actually happens in a GraphDB. Once you get the basics, then actually we will come to the RAG part, and we will come to the main research paper, which is from Microsoft.
Krish NAik: Alright, can we say Langraf? No, no, no, Langraf is totally different. See, guys, whenever you listen, Langraf, it will not come. Langraf is totally different stuff. And even Garapki will.
Krish NAik: How many of you used GraphQL?
Krish NAik: GraphQL is from Meta, like, an alternate of REST APIs.
Krish NAik: Anybody has used GraphQL?
Krish NAik: It's better than REST APIs.
Krish NAik: Okay, few people have used. Okay, yes.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, because that's why it's totally different, and Langrav totally different, don't get confused, okay?
Krish NAik: Hold it.
Krish NAik: Fine. So, let's start. So, I will, open mine.
Krish NAik: instance… Everybody, please, look into the screen. I will start creating the first instance of the cluster.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here…
Krish NAik: I hope everybody has installed. I have given enough time to do the installation of Neo4J desktop. So right now, I'm doing in the local one. In the cloud one, the only problem is you can create only one free instance. That's why I'm not looking into the cloud. But a very similar implementation that we'll be doing here.
Krish NAik: So, create instance, I will just click on that, and I will give some name.
Krish NAik: So, let's give anything G, R, A, P, H, graphs, Test.
Krish NAik: Okay, I think this is visible for everyone.
Krish NAik: graph test that I have given.
Krish NAik: Okay, and just give one password for him.
Krish NAik: So, I've given one password, and by default, the user will be Neo4j, the database user name that is coming.
Krish NAik: Okay, so graph test, and just pass the password, and then we will be creating.
Krish NAik: And quickly, it will be created.
Krish NAik: I think for everybody, the installation is done.
Krish NAik: Please let me know.
Krish NAik: For everybody, the installation is done. Updating, updating, updating, alright? Take 1 minute per, please complete that part.
Krish NAik: Everybody, okay, graph test, you can give any name, the name can be anything.
Krish NAik: For me, the main purpose is that to make a differentiation with SQL.
Krish NAik: Okay, and, these are your main credentials whenever you are, connecting. Okay, even through, like, in your Jupyter notebooks, when you will be making the connection, you will be using this connection string.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I think the server is up. I will just open this one. Okay, and please do change the port to 7474.
Krish NAik: Sorry, it has to be HTTP.
Krish NAik: Hmm…
Krish NAik: Okay, the port will be 7474. So, for example, if you see here, this particular port, 7687, is the default one.
Krish NAik: Okay, but to open the Neo4j browser, you… the port has to be 7474, and remove NEO4J, the protocol, the protocol will be HTTP.
Krish NAik: Okay, everybody please try to open the browser and then provide me, because I think for everybody, it should open. And then you have to actually pass the password that you have passed.
Krish NAik: Okay, so the connection URL, and I think the protocol.
Krish NAik: Yes.
Krish NAik: Please let me know. Everybody, can you guys see something like this?
Krish NAik: Everyone?
Krish NAik: Alright, fine. So, right now, if I try to just, zoom here…
Krish NAik: Okay, you can see that nodes are zero relationships are zero, and property keys are zero. Okay, so majorly three things that comes. Okay, so entity that I'm telling, so right now, how I think everybody knows about NER, named entity recognition that happens.
Krish NAik: So, most of the times, we define the entities, so by default, in any type of NER models, what are the common NERs that you have?
Krish NAik: common, NER, like, if I say some of the benchmarking data sets, like, the Kernel University data set 2003, so you have… no, no, no, Posh is a different thing.
Krish NAik: process part of speech, I'm talking about name entity recognition. Yes, the port is 7474.
Krish NAik: I think everybody can see.
Krish NAik: Yes, there you have something like I log, B log, need me to remember.
Krish NAik: P name, person, like, IP, VP, in that way.
Krish NAik: B stands for, like, beginning, yes, organization is there, location is there, person is there, miscellaneous is there. Okay, like, those are the default entities for a dataset which has been trained. So, similarly, whenever you are working with graph databases, you need to define those entities.
Krish NAik: One thing, right now, as we are working with AI, but before that, everyone who were working with graph databases, they used to define those entities.
Krish NAik: I will show you in LanChain, like, I can manually define those, or I can simply ask an LLM and whatever the LLM will give us. Okay, but it's a good practice if you can actually maintain all those entities across every document.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that will be a good practice. But, let's start, first of all, by defining a simple node. Because in the notebook, I have kept those examples.
Krish NAik: So, here you can see, the first thing, try new 4G with a movie graph. So, now this is a test one, if you guys want to test it, all the major commands and other things, like create, merge, constant. So, in one shot, everything has been provided. It's a very, very big
Krish NAik: I can say graph that will be created in one shot. But before that, let's focus on creating one by one step. I'm telling you because this is directly available, and you guys can do the execution. So this is the part where I'll be pasting all the commands. So, first of all, I will go to your main document.
Krish NAik: I think, where is that, GitHub? Let me just open your GitHub, yes.
Krish NAik: Now, here I have taken a simple example with respect to SQL versus Cypher. So, Cypher query language is the one that we'll be writing right now for any type of graph databases.
Krish NAik: Okay, the core language, it is, called as cipher query language, okay? Now, this is a high-level difference, okay, which has been shown here, but first of all, to at least make this work out, okay, we need to create some type of
Krish NAik: nodes, then only we can make it work. So, I think everybody has a new 4J. Okay, and right now, first of all, just copy this command. So, just this return.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, see, what I will do, I will just copy-paste it here.
Krish NAik: Just to check that everything is working fine or not. Where is that browser? Just wait. Neo4j? Okay, here, execute. And you will see, are you getting a result, like, message, NEO4J,
Krish NAik: And then the return type is 2.
Krish NAik: please let me know. You can directly copy-paste it from GitHub. That's why I've shared this particular file, from where you can get that table view.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, exactly the syntax is not related to SQL, but yes, the… in everywhere, the syntax will be different. I can see even in Falker, it is different, so in every, graph databases.
Krish NAik: Okay, it's not like a common standard for every place, it's exactly the same. So, every third-party provider has some type of difference, just remember that.
Krish NAik: Because if you are trying to perform it through a Python, because right now I have not used any Python drivers.
Krish NAik: I hope everybody get it.
Krish NAik: I'm not using any type of Python drivers, specific, like, then I will be installing, like, pip install, Neo4j. Right now, I'm directly hitting the query through the browser.
Krish NAik: Alright, so this was a simple test one. Now, the next step is to create a node. Okay, so for creating a node, you can simply copy this entire thing. So, right now, what I'm… I will be doing… so, this is the first step.
Krish NAik: Nodes are basically the entities in your graph that build up your small, like, social plus movie graph step-by-step. It means, I can say, the smallest unit in a graph.
Krish NAik: Okay, which is actually, having some type of working information.
Krish NAik: Okay? It's referred to as notes.
Krish NAik: Because without a node, in a graph database field, there will be multiple nodes, so we have to always start with some nodes. Nodes will be having some type of information, okay? So right now, the first node that I'm creating, this is called a percent node. You can see P, and then person.
Krish NAik: And for that person node, I'm telling create, it's basically the command through which I will be creating the node.
Krish NAik: the person node and this person node is having some properties, like name, Alice, age 30, role, data scientist, and then finally, return P. Return P is always not necessary, but right now I'll be returning the results so that you can actually see it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so you'll be getting something like this. If you won't return the results, you won't get the output.
Krish NAik: Okay, so you can simply copy this. No, no, no, this is not a movie graph, so this was a simple example, because,
Krish NAik: The default example of Neo4j is having a movie dataset, and I'll be showing you that example, don't worry. For now, this is the bare minimum, how to create a node.
Krish NAik: If you have two different nodes, then only you can create a relationship. It means that the edge, which is connecting both the nodes, that I showed you in the diagram. Okay, so I'm just creating that circle right now, and that circle is having some type of properties.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let me just copy this stuff.
Krish NAik: And then I will go to the browser.
Krish NAik: Okay, you can just paste it here.
Krish NAik: Okay? And right now, you will see node 0, relationship 0, and properties. Once I execute this, automatically you will see that one node will be created.
Krish NAik: Anitut is asking, when should we… I will come to that. Tell no, I'm not distressed.
Krish NAik: Whenever you feel that, you have something related entities, okay, then only. I will come to that, Anirot, don't worry. But for now, please do the executions, because, I won't be going in a depth, but at least the basic operations.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… Once I have done the execution, can you see a note with the person has been created?
Krish NAik: And this person note has been given a color, something like this, I can say the brown color, and then the property keys came, the age, the name, and the role.
Krish NAik: Please do have a check from your site.
Krish NAik: You are asking for the GitHub? Just wait.
Krish NAik: Everybody, please let me know.
Krish NAik: No, P is just a variable for now that I have taken.
Krish NAik: That's a return P. It's a variable. P is just a variable.
Krish NAik: See, guys? This is how syntactically it works.
Krish NAik: Can you create the… repeat the DB creation? DB creation is nothing, no. For DB, you have to just click on Create Instance, and then you have to, pass that, I think, password. By default, the user will be Neo4j, sir.
Krish NAik: Okay, just remember that password. You just need the password. Once the creation is done, you will see the running status. Just use this particular URL. So, they are 127, and 7474 is the code to open the new 4G browser. Only that's the stuff.
Krish NAik: Everybody, please, let me know in the browser. So, similarly, if you just fail the same command… okay, now, just wait.
Krish NAik: Might look.
Krish NAik: Here, let me take… if I want to create another person for now, let's remove… okay,
Krish NAik: Let me pass something like Lucid.
Krish NAik: 33.
Krish NAik: Okay, now see, P is just a variable, so it doesn't matter, because this is the return type, and it, the scope of P…
Krish NAik: Will be done, so you will see another node will be created.
Krish NAik: Can you see here two nodes right now?
Krish NAik: Here, actually, if you try to look, so previously, so two different nodes that will come.
Krish NAik: You can look into the table also from table also, or the raw view if you want. That is also fine, but right now I'm just showing you the graph.
Krish NAik: As simple as that.
Krish NAik: Because using the same command that you can actually do the execution, and so… Similarly, I've just created two nodes.
Krish NAik: Now, I can create, in one shot, more nodes, because right now, the… through the command that I am passing, so if you really look into… so, only one one that I am creating. So, inside create, you can pass the same thing, and you can actually make a return of multiple types. So, that will be the next example.
Krish NAik: I think this… It's clear for everyone.
Krish NAik: So, when I'm telling person, person is basically the node.
Krish NAik: And within the node, what are the properties?
Krish NAik: Name, age, and role. And finally, I'm returning that, so P acts as basically a variable for now.
Krish NAik: So, pretty much self-explanatory stuff.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, see, for two different…
Krish NAik: Okay, previously, one by one, I was doing it. Now, let me just pass everything at one shot.
Krish NAik: Okay, so B, C, Bob, Charlie, age, role, okay, so something like this, again…
Krish NAik: Okay, so here, if I try to pass it, you will see that automatically.
Krish NAik: To make a reload, just click on this nodes one, okay? Because in my system, in Mac, it doesn't exactly reload, so just click on that person. Automatically, you will see that, okay? Total. So previously, one one I created manually, and these two in one shot that I have created.
Krish NAik: Alright, so the mood creation part, I think it's self… everybody got it, because now…
Krish NAik: We will try to create another node, a different node, which is the movie node.
Krish NAik: Okay? Because previously, through this, we do the definition that, okay, this is the percent node. Now, let's create a different node.
Krish NAik: So, the type of node will be different.
Krish NAik: Because here, All the nodes that I have created, it comes under the person.
Krish NAik: Okay. Now, this time, a different node. So, where I'm telling, okay, the name of the node is movie. Movie means a different operation that I'm doing.
Krish NAik: Alright, can you see her now?
Krish NAik: Now, this node is different.
Krish NAik: And they are not interconnected. I have not done any type of interconnected, I'm just showing that, yes.
Krish NAik: If the type of the node is different, then they are totally different. Now, you can connect them through any type of relationship.
Krish NAik: Prathamesh is telling, I joined late.
Krish NAik: No coupons are shared.
Krish NAik: get, because I think coupon sharing has been really, like, we have stopped sharing coupons.
Krish NAik: Why the matrix is showing? No, no, see. Matrix is coming because I passed this command, no, see.
Krish NAik: I created a new node. Previously, every time I was creating this person node, but this time I changed the name of the node to movie, and in that, I kept the property as the matrix. Releasing here, 199 genre sci-fi rating. I hope you get that.
Krish NAik: Yes, Santosh, I can see your message.
Krish NAik: Why I only be getting your message?
Krish NAik: Prathamesh is asking, at one point it will be dynamic, right?
Krish NAik: You can make it dynamic, but if your documents are dynamic, then GraphRack doesn't really work.
Krish NAik: You need to have a defined… now, this is the main thing, like, you need to decide this according to your own set of documents that you'll be working with.
Krish NAik: If you feel that in every case this changes, then GraphRag is not a perfect use case.
Krish NAik: for you. Then, probably, you might be going ahead with VectorDB and other things.
Krish NAik: So, right now, I can say there is always some type of hierarchical. Okay, it means that with this particular node, there are certain properties which are being attached, but if you think something flat, just think about, if you have something, a big text corpus, okay, a big corpus of text.
Krish NAik: Just a book, for now, just think. Do you think that GraphRag will be helpful?
Krish NAik: Simple flat text, if you have. Generally, for flat type of data, GraphRag really doesn't work.
Krish NAik: It'll just waste of time in those cases. But if you have something where you have something much more linked, entities, for example, it can be social media. For example, anything in social media you can pick up one user. With that user, certain type of information, like how many followers are there.
Krish NAik: Okay, how many that user is following, okay, what are the different type of posts he has posted, so many…
Krish NAik: Entities are linked.
Krish NAik: In those cases, only it is helpful. But if your data is really flat, if there are no relationships that you can actually define it, it doesn't make sense to use graphs back.
Krish NAik: In those cases.
Krish NAik: Correct.
Krish NAik: Now, I have passed this, let's come back to the next part.
Krish NAik: Okay, I think this will return the full graph. Now, this is not, exactly. Now.
Krish NAik: If you want, you can do the execution, but really, this doesn't matter. It is like, select star, in your, SQL.
Krish NAik: Okay, like, select star that you do from your main table, everything that will be returned. So that's here, like, match and return, and it works in that.
Krish NAik: Rajat Karna is asking, as in home page, we can see the percent tab and the movie tab. Paul, can you answer my question? What is your question?
Krish NAik: Everybody. Just to know, I joined this course yesterday. How much more than 70% has been completed, Ravi?
Krish NAik: later on, like, for you, I will suggest go through the recordings, and 2.0, when it will be coming, you do the shift, Ravi. Okay.
Krish NAik: Is the syntax same for all graph TVs? No, no, no, no. Santosh, it will change. It's not like…
Krish NAik: And, like, in SQL also, you know that.
Krish NAik: It changes. In Postgres, it will be a bit different. The same thing in, if you move it with Microsoft.
Krish NAik: SQL servers, then it is different. So, every third-party provider, they will be having some type of differences.
Krish NAik: So, now…
Krish NAik: Now, Mar Thuma Syrian Church, Singapore is asking, how is match query showing? That is how it is being returned. It's just like select star from table. It will show all the notes. This is how it works, syntactically.
Krish NAik: This is query, yes, this is actually the query that I have passed.
Krish NAik: This is the executed query.
Krish NAik: Let's put where thing.
Krish NAik: No, no, no, here, I'm just returning everything, whatever the notes. Through this, you can return everything in one shot.
Krish NAik: All right. Now, see, that's all… these are syntaxes. These are nothing to discuss here. If you are working with, again, if I change the database tomorrow, again, the syntax will change. So, don't focus a lot on syntax.
Krish NAik: Because even for me, syntax, like, if I will be working with RAG, for me, the syntax won't play such a crucial role. Because right now, I'm directly working with the database, so it plays a crucial role. But actually, for my graph rag.
Krish NAik: It don't.
Krish NAik: Okay? Because this is the part where LLM will generate that. I hope everybody gets that.
Krish NAik: the LLM will actually generate this particular query.
Krish NAik: you will be passing a simple text, okay, and based on that, the graph query which will be generated, okay, it will be through an LLM, and based on that, the firing will happen.
Krish NAik: Alright, now let's move to the next part.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright, so here, the relationship right now. To create a relationship, we need some type of nodes and definition, okay? So, right here, so two different type of nodes. One is the Alice node, one is the matrix node.
Krish NAik: Okay, so it means that the movie node that I had. So here you can see P person, the person node, and the movie node. Two different nodes that I am connecting.
Krish NAik: Within that note, what are the actual properties that needs to be connected? The name, and the title.
Krish NAik: Alright, so, first of all, we need to do the matching, and then we'll be creating that.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let me just… Take that.
Krish NAik: Okay, so first of all, you have to do the match.
Krish NAik: Once the matching is done, then only you can create.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is very, very important.
Krish NAik: Till the time you don't do the matching, you can't create anything in any type of craft databases. So that's why Amherst Universe is telling the relationships and tax is not working. It should work.
Krish NAik: You can see here right now, yes, one relationship that got created. If you really see, it's working, because I created this relationship, the name was watched.
Krish NAik: Okay, and I can see that it got created. Everybody, please, provide me the confirmation right now.
Krish NAik: Because I feel that it should work, if it is working for me.
Krish NAik: Because right now, I just created a relationship, and simply…
Krish NAik: I gave.
Krish NAik: Rahul, saying is asking, please explain match. First, we are matching that, whether the nodes are available, and within that, the properties. If it doesn't match, then actually we cannot create the relationship. At any point of time, Rahul, you have to do a matching operation, then only you can create a relationship.
Krish NAik: Matching means, actually, it looks for the existence. If it is not existing, only then. Similarly, see, right now, create, because going forward, I'll be using the term merge. Merge means… just think about, if I try to create anything again and again, do you think that it will create?
Krish NAik: With the same node.
Krish NAik: I'm having already a person note with the name Alice.
Krish NAik: But if I try to create it again, so then comes an alternate of created merge. Means, if something is already existing that it won't be creating, automatically then you will be using, that particular keyword. So there are certain keywords, so that's why, step by step, we'll be looking into that.
Krish NAik: I'm just showing you a few examples. My task is not to teach, again, your Graph database near 4G. I'm just showing you, because the rest of the things, when I'll be doing it in drag, everything will be automatic.
Krish NAik: Alright. Now, probably you can think about if I'm passing something through a prompt. In that case, little bit relationship, and these things that needs to be defined.
Krish NAik: Now, let's get back.
Krish NAik: I think, movie note I have done, creating relationship I have done.
Krish NAik: Okay, then this is for visualization of the entire stuff, if you want to do it, do it. Okay, so, now this is written all the notes, already I've executed this once, so the return type will be exactly the same. It will show all the percent node, as well as your movie note, the matrix.
Krish NAik: That will also come. Now, this is filter by label and property, so this particular operation is there, so let me try to do the execution here.
Krish NAik: So let's get back here.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I'll be…
Krish NAik: Wiring the query. So here, match, okay, match on top of the… what are the conditions, first of all, we'll be looking into the person node, and in that person node, we'll be looking into the property where the age is 28, okay?
Krish NAik: If, more than 28, that we have kept it based on that, the name, age, and the rule, that will be returned.
Krish NAik: Yeah, so let me just execute, okay, and in both the cases, you can see, everywhere the condition is more than 28. So automatically, name, age, and rule is being returned. The same things in SQL also that you can do.
Krish NAik: Now, if you really look on top of which I have applied, so can I say that, yes, filtering by property, because I've applied the filter on top of a certain property, and based on that, I'm returning.
Krish NAik: I think it's pretty much self-explanatory, yes or no?
Krish NAik: The same thing you can apply on top of the movie node, because right now, I have a single one, the Matrix one, so there also you can apply based on release there, I think, one,
Krish NAik: Triple line.
Krish NAik: No, this one I have done.
Krish NAik: Now comes our… okay, now, this is the next step, which is basically traversing through a relationship. Because right now, this is traversing, or basically, this is a filtering operation on top of the node directly. But what about if we want to traverse any type of graph through a relationship?
Krish NAik: Now, worst is a relationship that I've already created between two nodes.
Krish NAik: Okay, and previously, if you remember, one was that Alice with the matrix. Okay? Now, here, through that relationship that I'll be performing a traverse operation.
Krish NAik: So, let me just pass it here. Okay, so here you can see match. First of all, we will be performing a match operation, P with person, and two different nodes. And nodes is connected with what relationship the watch? Can you see? Two nodes, with that you have, so…
Krish NAik: Right here, the relationship is our worst one, and the written type. If it is matching, then finally we'll be returning the name, p.name, as person, and then comes your title, the movie title. From this particular node, we are extracting the information and the rating.
Krish NAik: So, two information we are extracting from here. So, let me just execute this one.
Krish NAik: Okay, so the return type… P.name, which is coming as Alice.
Krish NAik: Then, because the relationship is connected with Alice and the Matrix movie. So both the things are returned, and this is the rating which is coming from that.
Krish NAik: So now, this is based on the relationship. So whenever you are working with a relationship, the node existence has to be there.
Krish NAik: Okay, so another type of filter operation based on that.
Krish NAik: There is no title.
Krish NAik: Because, when we have done the matching, their title was not existent, because of that.
Krish NAik: In our quilt.
Krish NAik: Because here, m.title as movie that we are doing. Because, see, when you see the title, this is the title. I hope everybody get…
Krish NAik: The command that we have pasted there, please look into the commands.
Krish NAik: Just wait, where is the command,
Krish NAik: When I created that movie node, I passed, your… this one.
Krish NAik: Can you see here the title?
Krish NAik: Whoever is asking that, there is no title or myth.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: how Charlie is coming. We have not inserted Charlie.
Krish NAik: Okay… Even I'm confused where Charlie is coming. I cannot see any Charlie here. Satish…
Krish NAik: Charlie, there is no Charlie data only.
Krish NAik: How Charlie will come.
Krish NAik: In your case, if you have given a different name, because this time, for me, it was at least during the, node creation, person node creation, if you have passed Charlie or something like that, then in your case, that will be the return type.
Krish NAik: This is the main written type, this says, focus on this one, don't focus on this one.
Krish NAik: This is that age 1. This is a different query.
Krish NAik: Don't get confused. That was for a different query.
Krish NAik: The queries are different, guys.
Krish NAik: See, always focus on the top one. So, here, I think with that age roll. See, here I passed it. If I… here it will come, Alice. Now, this is a different query, no? Then I executed different query. Now, this query, last time that I have done it, now, this was the… I hope everybody gets it.
Krish NAik: This is your old query that I have done in.
Krish NAik: Please look into the new query output.
Krish NAik: I know the UI and other stuff, you might get confused, but keep things, okay? So…
Krish NAik: Because that, Charlie, I thought, I thought you got the result here as Charlie, so I got confused.
Krish NAik: Fine.
Krish NAik: So that's why, like, if you have never really learned about craft databases, you need to explore it.
Krish NAik: Okay, because then, otherwise, it's a little bit overwhelming. That's why I thought about a little bit discussing rather than directly jumping into graph, right, so that at least you will have some idea that matches one keyword, create is there, little bit idea. It will be very less…
Krish NAik: But at least are directly jumping into GraphRag, but at least you should have a basic idea.
Krish NAik: with any graph database.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, traversing a relationship, I'm done. Okay, now, this is the same operation, okay, like this, but if you look into, this is through a limit. Right now, the return type will be exactly the same of this one.
Krish NAik: Okay, if you really look into, both the operations are exactly the same.
Krish NAik: So, if I pass this operation, the return type
Krish NAik: Because in my case, I have a… the amount of data is really less so. Both the output will be exactly the same one.
Krish NAik: Because I don't have… because if I will have more data, then for sure, the return type… here you can see, based on limit 5, you should get, total 5 results. But here, I have less amount of data, so only one is returned.
Krish NAik: Okay, so similarly, a few other patterns are there, multi-op traversal is there. Okay, this also, you can test it out.
Krish NAik: I've kept few things.
Krish NAik: So, here, matching, first of all, with the node. Okay, now, this news. So, do you think that we have news in our relationship?
Krish NAik: Yes or no?
Krish NAik: Okay? It's simply told, relationship does not exist. I hope you get it.
Krish NAik: When you are executing any query, always look into that, because I have not created any relationship nodes.
Krish NAik: You have to, first of all, create a relationship, then only it will work.
Krish NAik: Okay, I think this one, find relationship types dynamically, let's test it out. Because even… I think I have kept few things for initial testing, let me just pass it.
Krish NAik: Okay… I… A with B2 node.
Krish NAik: Let me see here, okay, alas watched that game again.
Krish NAik: Because here, the condition is kept. Dynamic retrieval, it was there.
Krish NAik: We find the relationship, but the, yes, that's why, like, from 2 is null right now.
Krish NAik: Not exactly from Mugu. We can execute from AltEnter inventory. Yes, AltEnter is also fine. I mean, it's totally up to you. You hit the run button, or anyone.
Krish NAik: The main thing is, see, I've kept few things that you can actually test it out.
Krish NAik: Cloud…
Krish NAik: Finally, like, I'll be deleting everything at any point of time if you want to delete, so this is the final command.
Krish NAik: to delete the entire thing. And now, whatever the stuff that I have done, if you want to do the final visualization, because
Krish NAik: Just twinked.
Krish NAik: Few cipher references with respect to… these are my executed commands.
Krish NAik: Just clothing every stuff, yes.
Krish NAik: Remove frame.
Krish NAik: I'll just delete everything now.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: 5 nodes deleted, deleted one relationship, okay? So, yes, pretty much everything is deleted right now. So, you can test it out, other things here. Okay, now this was a rough idea that I have shared with you exactly how things work in a graph database.
Krish NAik: Alright, you can explore UI and other things, okay, because here, all those relationships and everything that can be shown here. So here, with respect to, like, hierarchical layout and other layouts also that you can check.
Krish NAik: Alright, now I've deleted everything, so everything becomes zero, so…
Krish NAik: Leave it now, so I think we can proceed to the next part. So, first of all, now I will discuss the research paper, okay? So, first of all, let's look into the actual research from Microsoft, what they have been defined.
Krish NAik: It should delete a myth, because I know that is the main command to delete everything.
Krish NAik: match end, detach, delete end, it means that everything should be deleted. All of your nodes and all of your relationship. Please do have a check.
Krish NAik: Because the command should be same for everyone.
Krish NAik: Please let me know, can we start with the paper part now?
Krish NAik: Yes or no?
Krish NAik: This is… the main microphone.
Krish NAik: And in this paper also, they will be talking about a few, few, I can say, use cases. Not every use case is where you can actually put it.
Krish NAik: Sir, after that, we are going for end-to-end… what is end-to-end?
Krish NAik: There is nothing end-to-end simply, like, we'll be working with notebooks.
Krish NAik: This is not a project, you have to understand.
Krish NAik: Please check the syllabus.
Krish NAik: Please let me know, can we start with the paper?
Krish NAik: Because now…
Krish NAik: Because in your LangChain and Lama Index, you have direct retrievers, okay? Retrievers makes your life easier. You just need to take care of the prompt.
Krish NAik: In the prompt, how you are defining the relationship and the notes, those things you need to take care of.
Krish NAik: Alright, so here, they are talking about the use of RAG to retrieve relevant information from an external knowledge source enables LLMs to answer questions over private
Krish NAik: and or previously unseen document collections. However, RAC fails on global questions, okay? Directed at an entire text corpus, such as what are the main themes in the dataset. Now, this is a very high-level question. If you really try to understand.
Krish NAik: If somebody's asking this type of question, what are the main themes in the dataset?
Krish NAik: It can respond if it really has that information in a single chunk, or probably in 3-4 chunks.
Krish NAik: then it can respond. But if it is not available, and it has to actually infer, it means that this question needs to be broken down into other multiple questions. In those cases, it cannot actually respond back.
Krish NAik: Since this is inherently a query-focused summarization, QFS, now, this is the main task for which GraphRack came into existence, okay? This QFS.
Krish NAik: refer to as that query-focused summarization task, rather than an explicit retrieval task, because this is somehow different, because you are actually looking for something which is not directly available. It means that to get that, you need some other information, or probably through some type of entity or connection.
Krish NAik: It means that the information is there, but you have to make some meaningful question. Then only you can come and you can actually gather that information.
Krish NAik: Now, this QFS, we will explore a little bit more, so let me just complete the abstract part, then I will give you more examples with respect to QFS.
Krish NAik: Prior QFS methods, meanwhile, do not scale to quantities of text indexed by typical rack systems.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, simply, they are talking about
Krish NAik: prior QFS methods, so previously, like, according to their research, whatever, which has been used.
Krish NAik: They do not scale to quantities of text. It means that you keep on adding the data.
Krish NAik: at every point of time, it will be losing the context. It means that actually what the user is looking for, which is the, I can say, the global context, somehow it might be missing.
Krish NAik: Now, it's telling to combine the strength of these contrasting methods, we propose GraphRag, a graph-based approach to question answering over private text corpora that scales with both the generality of user questions and the quantity of user text.
Krish NAik: Now, they are telling that, here, but again.
Krish NAik: the benchmarking results are not really good so much. Our approach uses LLM to build a graph index in two stages. First, to derive an entity knowledge graph from source documents, then to
Krish NAik: pre-generate community summaries for all groups of closely related entities, okay? Now, just think about the approach that they have talked about.
Krish NAik: Our approach uses an LLM to build a graph index in two stages. The first is
Krish NAik: to, derive an entity knowledge graph from the source documents. So, what is your source document?
Krish NAik: In your case, what will be the source? If I say that I have a PDF, Okay, now…
Krish NAik: PDF is fine, but that PDF needs to be chunked, no?
Krish NAik: It means that chunks will be your actual, source, document.
Krish NAik: Okay? And then to pre-generate community summaries for all the groups of closely related entities, okay? Now here, certain algorithms will come, like, community-based algorithms are available in every graph database. I'll be talking about them. So, given
Krish NAik: a question, each community summary. So, community, when you think about, think about some type of thematic clusters.
Krish NAik: Okay, so thematic clusters means,
Krish NAik: Let's talk a little bit about this,
Krish NAik: at communities, because in every graph databases, there are algorithms which are based on these communities. Communities are a group of clusters. Okay, so for example, my main product is all about selling, some type of cell phones.
Krish NAik: In that cell phones, when I actually look into different type of reviews, I can say there will be some reviews where
Krish NAik: They might say something related to batteries. Okay, so I can say that, okay, so battery can be one thing.
Krish NAik: The other theme can be some type of issues with respect to network, some issues it can be… like, you have to think about clusters. Within that cluster, you'll be having some type of information. So those thematic clusters are referred to as communities.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, again, I will write it in the notes, but let me just complete this entire abstract part.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this community summaries for all the groups of closely related entities. Closely related means in the three-dimensional space, their clusters will be very close to each other.
Krish NAik: Given a question, each community summary, okay, community summary, or, like, one property of that particular cluster is used to generate a partial response before all partial responses are again summarized in a final response to the user.
Krish NAik: Now, this is a very time-taking task that they have referred here. Given a question, each community summary, so what is the community? Community refers here, basically, to the thematic cluster right now, okay, is used to generate a partial response.
Krish NAik: Before, all partial responses are again summarized in a final response to the user. Now, in real time, this… the response time is very, very high. So, practically, we won't be doing this. All partial responses are again summarized. So, this part, we won't be doing the implementation.
Krish NAik: Even in the original, like, graph rack, they have done it, but later on, everybody changed it, because it really takes a lot of time.
Krish NAik: And the latency increases.
Krish NAik: So, for a class of global sense-making questions over datasets in 1 million token range, we show that graph rack leads to substantial improvement, but again, when they say substantial, it's very, very less. Okay, over a conventional rack baseline for both comprehensiveness and diversity of generated answers.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now, really, like, if you look into some benchmarks.
Krish NAik: Okay, because at the end of the day, what matters to me is much more about the benchmarks. Now, every type of task that they have taken, it's not on top of some type of generic dataset. It means the task that they have taken, for that, they have created some dataset.
Krish NAik: Which is not used by any other RAG benchmark.
Krish NAik: You have to understand, like, when somebody's talking about these type of papers. It means that these are very much customized papers. Now, see, here they are talking about a dataset news article, and podcast transcripts.
Krish NAik: Now, in any main research paper, if you search about this dataset, you will never get it.
Krish NAik: Because for this particular research paper, only they have customized it. You have to understand this part. When something is much more customized according to some research. Because in that research, they want to prove that, yes, this is something good.
Krish NAik: Now, they have brought… they have a controlled setting, that we call it.
Krish NAik: the entire environment with control behavior, setting that they have done it. Because, when I say that, okay, now this is my formula, now the idea is that my formula should be tested with every other formula of any other data set. That's how AI happens.
Krish NAik: But, generally in most of the graph… rack paper, you will see that there is no standardized data set.
Krish NAik: They have created their own version, so for sure.
Krish NAik: They will be creating their own versions, because the entity, relationship, and those things needs to be defined.
Krish NAik: In a generic data, it will be pretty much flat corpora. So, there, they cannot use graph databases.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why customized data sets that they have kept it.
Krish NAik: Now, here, average number of clusters that they are talking about, average number of clusters, clusters mean thematic clusters. Like, based on a certain topic, clusters can be created.
Krish NAik: Okay, and then, and, see, conclusion acknowledgements, okay, all those references will come. Now they will be talking about few
Krish NAik: approaches, see, here. Entity and relationship extraction approach, how they have used, like, GPT-4. Here, they have used self-reflection, I think everybody remembers, we have gone through self-reflection.
Krish NAik: Yes, guys? How many of you remember self-reflection?
Krish NAik: Okay, so even in their implementation, they have kept self-reflection. Okay. Now, this is a community detection. Community detection refer to a cluster detection, like, portal. How many type of themes you have? Because based on themes, you create the clusters. So, some root-level communities that they have created. But again,
Krish NAik: not so much optimal. They are talking about some context window selection. Really, like,
Krish NAik: the context window will grow bigger and bigger, because 128K, one year back, it was…
Krish NAik: Good, but right now… what is the latest one?
Krish NAik: Yes, right now in 2026, what is the context window that is going around?
Krish NAik: 1 million. Okay, so 1 million tokens, generally, like, Cloud4.6, and they have it. And what is the first Transformers model? So, what was the context window there?
Krish NAik: the first original Transformers.
Krish NAik: which was created for machine translation. The attention is all you need. What was the context window there?
Krish NAik: Yes, people say.
Krish NAik: Because for my… from my other batch, people are telling correct.
Krish NAik: Few people, okay. It was 512. Few people are telling 512 is good to know, but, 512 it was.
Krish NAik: So, you can see, like, if you try to divide 1 million divided by 512, it will be, like, close to 2,000%, I think, growth will be there.
Krish NAik: Okay, huge growth.
Krish NAik: Like, just in one year, it has been pretty much doubled right now.
Krish NAik: Thank you.
Krish NAik: No, no, the number of hits doesn't matter.
Krish NAik: Raul.
Krish NAik: those 12 words are for multi-year retention, and the dimension is that embedding dimensions. I'm talking about max sequence length.
Krish NAik: Because right now, for the past 3 years, we have been using the term context window, but actually, it is referred to as max sequence length in any Transformers architecture, if you guys get it, okay? So I'm talking about the max sequence length.
Krish NAik: Alright. Now, context window will increase, so really, this thing doesn't matter to us a lot.
Krish NAik: Okay, and then see. Now, again, pretty much based on their customized data set, they are showing the answers.
Krish NAik: like, in real time, if somebody uses, I don't feel that…
Krish NAik: It will work so much good.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why you can systemate prompts and everything that they have kept it according to their control settings.
Krish NAik: So, that's why I'm not really a very big fan, always. But yes, I know graphs databases can really work where you have your entire data in a certain structure.
Krish NAik: From your dataset, you can actually create relationship. Generally, for social media data sets, financial data sets, easily it can be done.
Krish NAik: Because they always maintain a structure, it's not, like, flat. There is no structure at all, or no type of entities.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why you guys can go through the paper. There are a few other papers also. Every paper, you will see that customized things that they have brought, which are not used in any other data sets.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, let's start with the most simplest, example.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I think…
Krish NAik: So let's… little bit, those theoretical things which have been discussed in the paper, I'll be talking about those things, like what is community and other stuff. Then we will jump into our core implementation.
Krish NAik: iPad web, airplane.
Krish NAik: So Aniroth, if the context window on the model increases, rats, not, that's useful.
Krish NAik: Always remember the context window size increases the response time from the LLM increases, so that your latency will increase.
Krish NAik: That's why we do pruning. There's the concept of pruning.
Krish NAik: In the entire field of deep learning, we do pruning.
Krish NAik: Like, in computer vision, we do channel pruning.
Krish NAik: In NLP, we do weight pruning. Similarly, in RAG, we do token pruning.
Krish NAik: pruning concepts.
Krish NAik: Okay, I met,
Krish NAik: No screen. Alright, I have started sharing the iPad, just wait again, I will share. Sometimes it happens, with that iPad via…
Krish NAik: Just click… Alright, I hope now it will start.
Krish NAik: Alright, so now I think you guys can read. Okay. So, the first, all about these particular clusters that they have talked, okay?
Krish NAik: You have to think, the main thing in the paper that they are referring is that, QFS, which is query-focused summarization, okay?
Krish NAik: Because in every… that's the main purpose of this particular paper, QFS.
Krish NAik: Query. Focused…
Krish NAik: summarization. So, when I'm talking with respect to this, it means that your questions that you will be asking, it won't be directly available in your chunks.
Krish NAik: Okay, it means that from that question, so from that Q1, you need to make inference to, like, probably some Q1.1 will come, Q1.2 will come, 1.3 will come.
Krish NAik: Okay? And then, now, these will go, and actually it can be referred to some chunk. It can be referred to some chunk.
Krish NAik: The need can be referred to some chunk.
Krish NAik: But directly, if I say, With this one, you cannot get it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why in between that, that's why this is referred to as that global.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: And these are referred to as your local.
Krish NAik: Directly based on your global query, it becomes much more harder. Okay, so that's why if you have some type of entity or relationship through which it is defined, it becomes much more easier.
Krish NAik: Because your normal vector retrieval won't work in this particular scenario from directly global to your chunking mechanism in your vector DB. That particular relationship is not possible.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, the next thing that comes is community detection.
Krish NAik: Okay, so communities, when I'm telling that, community detection in every graph database is
Krish NAik: wherever, whether it's AWS, everywhere. This community…
Krish NAik: Okay? For every, community, there are algorithms, okay? And generally.
Krish NAik: These are referred to as CDA.
Krish NAik: Community, in simple terms, you can think about clusters also.
Krish NAik: Okay, clusters also you can think.
Krish NAik: But actually, they use the term, communities a lot, community detection algorithm. And exactly, if I say that, okay, these type of detection algorithms, what do they do?
Krish NAik: they will be perform some type of clustering operation, okay? So, like, simply, I can say these algorithms will perform clustering operation.
Krish NAik: Now, this particular clustering operation once you do the execution. Then, finally.
Krish NAik: you will be getting some type of C1, C2, C3, C4. Okay? So, you have… we will have… you will, first of all, you will have your entire data. On top of the data, you will be applying some algorithm
Krish NAik: on your graph databases, it's called as, like, your CDA, the community detection. From your community detection. Finally, you will be getting your clusters. Now, these clusters will be thematic.
Krish NAik: I think everybody understands thematic.
Krish NAik: Based on some theme.
Krish NAik: Okay, according to your data, okay, you will try to get some type of themes.
Krish NAik: which will be pretty much unique. So, for example, with respect to mobiles that I told, okay, like, yeah, if you are actually looking into a review-based dataset in that review, it can be battery-based, it can be network-based.
Krish NAik: It can be some other issues with respect to your mobile, it can be based on heating issue. In that way, like, you will be defining some type of themes, okay? So, each cluster will be related to some type of themes.
Krish NAik: Okay, and whenever you are, processing any query, so…
Krish NAik: From that query, we will try to understand the theme.
Krish NAik: Okay, and once we get the theme, then actually we go inside and finally perform that search operation.
Krish NAik: Because if we cannot get the theme.
Krish NAik: It takes a very, very long time. This is the very similar way, through some type of optimization that we can do it.
Krish NAik: Okay, it means that based on your query, you have to always find, like, what is the theme that we are referring.
Krish NAik: based on… it can be based on keyword, like, this part is just like metadata filtering in your vector DB.
Krish NAik: If you can filter it, it says much better.
Krish NAik: It is like metadata filtering, not exactly, so that's why I would use the term like.
Krish NAik: Because, based on your query, if you cannot figure it out, and if you have so many thematic clusters.
Krish NAik: The response time, again, it will increase.
Krish NAik: Okay? So that's why, like, the next level is basically the optimization. Theme means semantic? No, no, there is nothing semantic here.
Krish NAik: based on the dataset, it can be based on, like, anything. According to your data, you have to find that. What are the core themes according to which you can define? And themes are core actual entities.
Krish NAik: Now, amethystealing pruning as an optimization of the parameters neurons. Yes, that's the main purpose of it.
Krish NAik: Current state of the models are at 2 million to 10 million, 2 films present day. It depends upon, like, 1 trillion parameters models are doing great a month.
Krish NAik: Perfect.
Krish NAik: Can we say theme means… okay, there is no semantic, see, whenever we say semantic, it means some type of vector stuff that comes into the picture, subtana. So, there is, right now, no vector stuff.
Krish NAik: So that's why I won't use the term, semantic. Thematic, why I'm telling? Because this is according to your data theme, because every dataset will have its own unique theme.
Krish NAik: Because, yeah, according to your use case, for example, if you're working in some, like, in a pharmacy-based data set you have, and there you are working in drug discovery, for sure, in your case, it will be different themes.
Krish NAik: You have to understand, so themes will be related and unique to the core data that will be, that we'll be working on.
Krish NAik: So, if I say that, what is the mean purpose of using Graphrack? Can anybody tell me?
Krish NAik: What is the main purpose?
Krish NAik: to solve the problem of QFS, okay? So, if I say, in final terms, if I want to do that.
Krish NAik: graph… A lag.
Krish NAik: What it will solve?
Krish NAik: global.
Krish NAik: This is written even in the abstract of the paper.
Krish NAik: Okay, and global sense-making. This is the idea that it will be solving. And how it will solve?
Krish NAik: Bilingger?
Krish NAik: Graph database.
Krish NAik: Now, this is a constant. You cannot use anything here, because in a graph database only, you can have a node-entity-based relationship. Through that only, it is possible. So, a lot of things are controlled in this paper, I feel. You don't have
Krish NAik: a lot of free ants to do a lot of optimizations. So, based on the core implementations of Langchain, and I can say Lama Index, the retrievers, and I can say the chains are available, which will be using it in our practical.
Krish NAik: So, Amit is telling, what does Global Sense… Global Sense means this one that I told.
Krish NAik: This becomes your global, I don't know. This is your global query that came.
Krish NAik: Now, that global needs to be actually broken down into multiple local. Then only you can actually get the core information. I hope you get it, what I'm referring at to global. Because directly bypass that global query, it cannot understand, because that information is not there only in the chart.
Krish NAik: You need to make that information available through your local queries, I can say.
Krish NAik: And local queries right now, it means that through your graph entity relationship, that it will try to fetch the data.
Krish NAik: Now, Amit is asking, Microsoft data physical to Warning, graph indexing can be an expensive operation. Please read all the documentation. Yes, everywhere, even here also, this is really dangerous operation.
Krish NAik: Because, see,
Krish NAik: If I don't know the entities, then what will happen? I will show you right now, in the practicals, because most of the times, my assumption will be, I will pass to the LLM, okay? LLM will figure it out, but think that in a database, everybody is passing different set of documents. Do you think the entities will be same?
Krish NAik: Do you think that any type of relationship, it means, again, it has to be some type of controlled environment. It means that when you know that, okay, this is the format of the document, okay, and this set of format will be repeated. For example, financial contracts.
Krish NAik: Okay, legal contracts, anything that you can think about. Then, similarly, like, some type of invoices. Okay, now you have to think in that way. Where you feel that something has to be standardized, if there are new standards only, it becomes very hard to define the entities.
Krish NAik: And at every point of time, if you upload 10,000 documents, and 10,000 different documents are different type of entities, then GraphRag really, it doesn't make sense.
Krish NAik: I hope you get that.
Krish NAik: Okay, now we will try to do the same thing that I told right now.
Krish NAik: that uses a lot of tokens, Abhishek. Okay, I'll be showing you, because, see.
Krish NAik: Right now, I'm telling…
Krish NAik: based on a document, you'll be creating the entities, but actually, in real life, what will happen? That document will have multiple chunks.
Krish NAik: Okay, so actually it becomes chunk-level. I will show you that without async, how much time it takes and with sync, because, that's why you will automatically understand that if I have 200 chunks.
Krish NAik: To analyze one chunk, and from there, to get the entities, it takes a very, very long time.
Krish NAik: Yeah, so I will be showing you all these things practically. So, I don't feel that it's always a very good solution, but again, people are using it, so let's explore that part.
Krish NAik: Now, everybody please take a clone of this, repo, I think you guys have done it.
Krish NAik: Yes or no? Because this is the first one getting started with CraftRack, this is the notebook that I'll be executing. Everybody, please take a glow.
Krish NAik: Please take a clone and then do an UV sync.
Krish NAik: UV Sync. I think everybody knows now UV Sync. Going forward, I'll be using UV Sync a lot.
Krish NAik: no requirements file is here. I've added requirements, so generally what happens if you have a requirement, you can do uvadd hyphen r, requirement.txt.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that is also fine, but do that UVSync. I have already shared the 2ML file, so I don't think there will be any major problems.
Krish NAik: Okay, I have a few other libraries also, I was planning to get Llama, but, I think I've kept only till Langchen part. Okay, so everybody, please, do the installation, and then let me know that, yes, my notebook is ready.
Krish NAik: Everybody, please let me know.
Krish NAik: Could you please, file I joined late?
Krish NAik: Alright, file I can share.
Krish NAik: Please do an UV sync, and then let me know. Installation, yes, it will take some time, it's UV. At least I know under one minute it should be done.
Krish NAik: Actually, I think this is of no use.
Krish NAik: Everybody, please, be sure, because right now, I will just create another instance.
Krish NAik: For this instance, I have to do some configuration, that's why.
Krish NAik: The old instance, I will… you can keep it also, or you can delete it also, every time you will be having that connection URL.
Krish NAik: Yep.
Krish NAik: Let me just delete the old one.
Krish NAik: Alright, here I'll be giving a name, GraphRack for now, okay, and Neo4j is fine.
Krish NAik: The password, I think, and just do it.
Krish NAik: Please set your ENV file. In your ENV file, you'll be getting it, so I think…
Krish NAik: I have given, Ragbatch 123 all right.
Krish NAik: Okay, I'm just creating a new one.
Krish NAik: You guys' screen is not shared, okay, alright, then what I'm sharing.
Krish NAik: Now, this is the stuff that we get, so please do have a check on this.
Krish NAik: I just created, this graph one.
Krish NAik: Okay, and this is my ENV file, exactly how it looks like.
Krish NAik: Boom.
Krish NAik: I'm using the OpenAI API key already, I've shared those stuff with you. You can have a look.
Krish NAik: So, please take your time, please do the configuration, set up your .env file, Keep your API keys there.
Krish NAik: UV is taking a lot of time, lot of time… Okay, first time it will take, I think next, time it will… fine, let's wait.
Krish NAik: Because you need to do the execution.
Krish NAik: In the meantime, see, UV is getting installed, fine, just delete the old one, okay, and create a new instance.
Krish NAik: It's better to keep it fresh.
Krish NAik: Right? Just create a new instance. Otherwise, if you have deleted everything from the old one, you can reuse that.
Krish NAik: Okay, so if it's clean. Otherwise, stop.
Krish NAik: Stop the instance, delete it, and create a new one. Otherwise, just stop it and create a new one. Okay, the main purpose is, you should have a blank one. There should not be any type of data that we have fed previously
Krish NAik: Just for testing. It should be a blank instance. There should not be any type of data, that is the…
Krish NAik: Final thing.
Krish NAik: Alright, so now in my case, stop, okay.
Krish NAik: Everybody please let me know that are you guys creating a new one, or reusing the old one?
Krish NAik: In the chat.
Krish NAik: Because there is one configuration which we have to do it.
Krish NAik: Okay, please take your time, take 2 minutes, please create a new one.
Krish NAik: And I think by that time, your UV installation?
Krish NAik: Should be done.
Krish NAik: everybody, delete the whole instance and create a new one for now. Because for every task, I need a new instance, so, like, you can create a… like, deletion is not necessary later on after the class, but for now, just create another one.
Krish NAik: Okay, and I'm just telling you one thing. Whenever you're creating, for example, if you have 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6 instances, always focus on this connection URL.
Krish NAik: This is very, very important, because for every instance, this URI will be different. In my case, if I show you my ENV, I pasted here, this is the URI.
Krish NAik: Okay, and if you look into here, okay, now, see, this is my OpenAI API key that I've pasted, then bold. What is bold?
Krish NAik: Bolt is the protocol which is used by Neo4J, just like JDBC in Java, if you think about. Okay, it's such protocol, very specific to their software that they use.
Krish NAik: Okay, and then comes your username, and then comes your, whenever you are creating that instance in your local, the password that you have passed.
Krish NAik: Okay, so please do pass this information.
Krish NAik: And, because I think your… Core execution, okay…
Krish NAik: This is the main execution. If it fails, then it will create a problem.
Krish NAik: Neo 4G? Oh, no, no, 74 and 74 is only for opening the browser.
Krish NAik: that Neo4J browser, otherwise debajyoti you don't need. Then comes the default one.
Krish NAik: Here, if you see, it's, 7687, okay? The same one, I have kept it, here, 7687.
Krish NAik: Only the protocol has been changed to bold.
Krish NAik: And,
Krish NAik: In local, they use Bolt. In cloud, if you try to move, then they will be using NEO.
Krish NAik: So, once you guys have done the configuration, please let me know.
Krish NAik: I think installation should be done for everyone.
Krish NAik: Because I know a few more packages, actually, you can remove the Llama Index. I was planning to take Llama Index also.
Krish NAik: So, those packages also have included. But actually, it is not required. You can delete them from 2ML fight.
Krish NAik: If you want the installation to be faster.
Krish NAik: issue with PDF Miner did not download, separately, see, if some package is not working, do it separately.
Krish NAik: generally, like, my log file is based on Mac, so… that's why I've not shared UV.log file. I thought about you guys will be creating your own lock file. When you do an UV sync, automatically that file will be created.
Krish NAik: Where are we passing the DB name? DB name, where are we passing?
Krish NAik: Okay, we are not passing, it's by default, so whenever I create any instance, you can see the default is Neo4j.
Krish NAik: Rakesh, we are not passing any DBN, okay?
Krish NAik: We will be only passing the connection URI. Through that, we can access it.
Krish NAik: Amit is asking, does UV use as many threads? Is it fast?
Krish NAik: No, no, no, the backend of UV is different, it's written in Rust.
Krish NAik: That's why it's fast.
Krish NAik: Gagan is asking, vectorless is… that's a different one. But again, vector list really doesn't work for a diverse type of data, okay? If your data, again, there also… a lot of restrictions are there. It's not for every type of data, it works.
Krish NAik: Vectorless, page index, I'll be taking one extra session, okay, after March, there.
Krish NAik: Because, I think 3 to 4 extra sessions that I'll be taking, few topics are there, which are very, very small, like, only 1 hour topic for those things. Then I'll be showing you… because, again, it's a paid one, you have to understand it's a paid stuff, so… but I'll be showing you the demo.
Krish NAik: Agentic, right?
Krish NAik: Yes, Agent Tekara, even today's one will be agents, a little bit of agents. I have added Lagra.
Krish NAik: Agent IGRAG will come after that.
Krish NAik: Everybody, please let me know that your instance is up and running.
Krish NAik: You have to do one small configuration, otherwise you might get errors, so that's why I'm asking everyone. Is the installation part done for everyone?
Krish NAik: So this should be same only.
Krish NAik: The new, instance port is… no, no, no, see, the port will be exactly which is written here.
Krish NAik: What is written in your Neo4J desktop, please pass that exact port.
Krish NAik: Don't write 7474. 7474 is only for, accessing the browser.
Krish NAik: Okay, so 7474 is only for accessing the browser. Please, pass the correct connection URL.
Krish NAik: Yes, I will take an extra class for PG Index.
Krish NAik: I'm actually… I was actually applying for a few extra classes. Next month, like, March… Till after reliable.
Krish NAik: Yes, RAG and, like, vector-less concept is here, so that will be discussed.
Krish NAik: Please let me know, I think I've given enough time.
Krish NAik: Okay? For, doing the installation part. So…
Krish NAik: So, let's start executing from the first cell.
Krish NAik: The first cell is just looking into the environments and those things.
Krish NAik: input away.
Krish NAik: load.env, OpenAI API key.
Krish NAik: Then comes your new 4G URI, username, password, these things, I have already passed it here. From here, it will be picked up.
Krish NAik: Now, the next thing that comes.
Krish NAik: Now… now tell me how many of you are getting this error, APOC error, APOC.
Krish NAik: Let me know. Like, then, again, if you are getting this error, I have to provide you the solution.
Krish NAik: Okay, Asantosh, alright. Others, please let me know.
Krish NAik: Because I feel that most of you should get that.
Krish NAik: Getting it? All right. All right. Others, everybody please do the execution and then tell me, getting, getting, getting, then I will…
Krish NAik: Okay, running cell, running cell, okay, I did install the plugin from TV already, yes. You have to do the installation, so directly, here you have to go, three dots are here, click on that, and plugins will come. Here, just click on this epoch plugin.
Krish NAik: Just do that, okay? So once you have done the installation, then please restart.
Krish NAik: If you have done the restart, you just need to do the installation of this in both the notebooks.
Krish NAik: You need to take care of this particular operation.
Krish NAik: So once the notebook is up, then again, I will restart the kernel in my VS Code, and then I think I can start the execution.
Krish NAik: It takes some time.
Krish NAik: First, you have to stop the instance sort of, then you have to delete the instance.
Krish NAik: Later on, do the deletion. Right now, just create a new one.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I think I will just restart this, restart.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: No, I think, again.
Krish NAik: Okay, and here you can see this time.
Krish NAik: I'm not, getting any errors, I think.
Krish NAik: Yes, this part is done.
Krish NAik: So, what I've done, first of all, I'm just looking into the credentials. Once the credentials are there, I'm initializing my Langchain Neo4j, object, which is the graph object, and I'm making the connection to my local instance. Then come enhanced schema. Okay, so right now.
Krish NAik: I don't have any schema, but later on, after passing the data, in those cases, I'll be making it, then comes sanitize is equal to true, like, clean, unsafe characters, and refresh. Now, this is very important, refreshing the schema. So, whenever I'll be calling this, just think about if you have done any changes. Okay, automatically, the schema will be updated.
Krish NAik: So, this refresh schema is important if you're making any changes, if you're creating any nodes, if you're creating any relationship. So, automatically, that schema gets updated. Otherwise, if you make it false, then the old one, so initially it is blank, I have nothing, so always it will be blank. The return type.
Krish NAik: Next, I'm getting an LLM, so your OpenAI, embeddings and chat OpenAI, two imported, I think, basic boilerplate, everybody should be familiar. Then I have a piece of text.
Krish NAik: Initially, we will start with random documents, because here I am not passing any PDF, just what I have passed.
Krish NAik: the document class from LanChain, okay? And let me just load it there.
Krish NAik: Okay, something with related to Elon Musk, born businessman. Now, this is a simple piece of text. On top of that, if I want to create some type of relationship, how to do that?
Krish NAik: So, you have the Langchen experimental module. Inside that, you have your graph transformer, okay? And I'm importing my LLM graph transformer. Now, this is the job of this particular transformer to do it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so right now, I'm just initializing it. I'm not doing anything, just initializing my LLM graph transformer.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: So everybody, please check, this cell might not work for many of you.
Krish NAik: If it is not working, please let me know, because I think this is the main package, langchen-experimental.
Krish NAik: Here you have this… So, please let me know it's working or not.
Krish NAik: Yes, paper install, blank gen experimental. It's already there, I think, in your, 2ML file.
Krish NAik: So I'm selling, could not connect to Neo Forager, please ensure the UL is… is the URL, check the URL.
Krish NAik: Could not connect to Neo 4J.
Krish NAik: Please let me know.
Krish NAik: Now, this is a graph transformer implementation that they have taken, actually. Okay, if I show you this implementation…
Krish NAik: Just wait.
Krish NAik: That's why it's experimental, it's not in the stable one. Till now, they have not moved it.
Krish NAik: Because, again, dummy implementation, that type of thing
Krish NAik: And later on, this implementation actually will be moved under.
Krish NAik: Oh.
Krish NAik: Alright, so pretty much zero references here also. In the newer one, it has not been added, I feel. Later on, through that, a separate package that has been built, but again, nobody's using this particular package.
Krish NAik: Okay, previously, it was there just to make
Krish NAik: that particular implementation, and I feel that this implementation is good, but again, nobody is adopting it directly, okay, because you have the core implementation here, and if you actually look into, you will see that this is the schema, what will be the node schema? What will be the relationship schema?
Krish NAik: So, now, the purpose of that node, main transformer is to define this node, define this relationship, to create this. So that's why you are giving it a particular structure through PyTentictor, okay? Now, these are the things that needs to be taken care of.
Krish NAik: Because I'm passing just blank text. So I'm telling that, okay, you need to follow this rule for the generation. That is the main purpose of that graph transform.
Krish NAik: Neo4J username is not custom, it's by default Neo4j.
Krish NAik: Okay, and now I'll be showing you, the prompt generation.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here they kept it, see, you are a top-tier algorithm designed for extracting information in JSON, structured formats to build a knowledge graph. Can you see here? I'm just telling you, like, what is the main purpose of that LLM graph transformer, so that you guys can get it, because I'm using an LLM to generate those relationships.
Krish NAik: So, because this implementation is directly there, but purely, if you look into
Krish NAik: So this is how, through a prompt, they are doing the generation.
Krish NAik: How many of you got it? Exactly what these guys are trying to do.
Krish NAik: People are getting error in new 4G only?
Krish NAik: Abhijita is asking, can you please repeat about the epoch issue? For the epoch issue, go to your local instance, and for example, three dots are there, click on that, and click on Plugins. You will see epoch is there, just install it.
Krish NAik: Done.
Krish NAik: Abhijayk, okay, for that.
Krish NAik: Now, Murthaza, you got the idea with respect to that LLM core. That's why I showed you this part only, because it's actually pretty much prompt, and this is the job of the LLM to extract those entities.
Krish NAik: Because what will be the node? What will be relationship? What will be the properties of those nodes? Those things, LLM will do.
Krish NAik: Now, this is actually a very expensive task, when you really think about when I'll be looking into every chunk.
Krish NAik: And based on that chunk, so it really takes a lot of time.
Krish NAik: So, first of all, please tell me, guys, For how many OPU…
Krish NAik: everything till now that I have done is getting executed.
Krish NAik: Ping this URL, Satish, which URL? Alright, this is a open source implementation of this one already. I will share this.
Krish NAik: Even, like, my reference was from this one.
Krish NAik: So, I share.
Krish NAik: Because here, we are basically asking the LLM to figure it out. What will be the nodes, what will be the relationship, what will be the entities.
Krish NAik: Alright, now see, I have done the initialization, the next thing is basically convert to graph documents.
Krish NAik: There, I'll be actually passing my main document here. You can see the actual piece of text with respect to Elon Musk that I have. Let me just pass it here.
Krish NAik: Okay, so through this LLM underscore transformer, convert to graph is the actual function through which we'll be doing the conversion. It will take a little bit of time.
Krish NAik: I see the node's ID type, okay, yes.
Krish NAik: I'll write some pattern, type of identic warning that came, it's fine, not an issue. So you can look into this graph documents, nodes, relationship, everything.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here, the graph… Documents.
Krish NAik: You can look into the,
Krish NAik: Right now, current.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Looks like a single piece. So generally, right now, it's only one, okay? And these are some of the nodes… so these are all the nodes which are being shown. You can look into only a few of them.
Krish NAik: You feel…
Krish NAik: Alright? Don't look into everything. If you want to look into the relationship now, these are all which has been done by the LLM.
Krish NAik: Okay, so really, I don't feel that all the things, just look into a few, so that you get an idea.
Krish NAik: I think…
Krish NAik: All right. Now, with respect to the mean, if you look into the mean nodes, okay, nodes with respect to relationship.
Krish NAik: So, first of all, if you look here into your main nodes, Okay, node ID.
Krish NAik: Alright, Elon Dreamers, then OneNote for SpaceX, one for Tesla, then X, The Boring Company, X AI, Neuralink, OpenAI, Forbes, Pretoria, Oscar. Can you see here? Like, I can say that, yes, the LLM has done it.
Krish NAik: To a certain extent. I feel that, yes, everything is quite, a bit different. So really, like, X Corporation and X AI, actually both are two different entities.
Krish NAik: Okay, so based on that, I feel that, yes, they have done it correctly.
Krish NAik: there won't be any break. Directly, I'll be continuing on, okay?
Krish NAik: Please do have a check, okay? Now, Shug is asking, node ID is equal to Queen's University at Kingston.
Krish NAik: Node ID, because these are the core nodes.
Krish NAik: Then, in the next step, we have the relationship, in that, I think it can be defined through a relationship.
Krish NAik: So, if you ask me to look into all the relationship.
Krish NAik: Okay, somewhere around Queen's University that you were telling.
Krish NAik: I think some University of Pretoria is here.
Krish NAik: Okay, which is basically one type of organization. University of Pennsylvania, Stanford is here.
Krish NAik: But, where is Queens University? It will be there, I think, but…
Krish NAik: Alright, now this particular information, if you actually move it to a graph, okay, you can actually do the visualization in a better way.
Krish NAik: Okay. Because right now, using that, I have just generated this… Can you see, see, from this data, you have converted to this data. How much… this was the core purpose?
Krish NAik: Now, think that next time, if I ask… if I pass some… a different piece of text, do you think that the same entities will be coming?
Krish NAik: How many of you think that if I just change a piece of text, you will be having very similar node ID information or anything?
Krish NAik: it will be totally different. So, like…
Krish NAik: If you have such type of things where your structure is always maintained and standardized.
Krish NAik: GraphRag is good. If you feel that at every point, if your structure changes, it becomes problematic. Most of the times, the real world, like, you cannot make your solution, then, like, an open solution.
Krish NAik: It also be closed one only for internal purposes that you are using.
Krish NAik: Shiva, BRK, no break, no break, man. We will continue.
Krish NAik: Because, I hope everybody gets what the LLM has done. First of all, it basically created those mood and those relationships.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: No?
Krish NAik: Now, this is a sample example with respect to a simple one. Now, in the next step, we'll be loading a dataset directly.
Krish NAik: So, I'm just showing you exactly how this is the dataset.
Krish NAik: You guys have the link, you can open it. This is… Data…
Krish NAik: Can I say, let's see, in this data also, there is movie ID, release, title, actors, director, genre, then you have your IMDB rating. Now, this is the same dataset which is available in the cloud version, as well as the local version of Neo 4G.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I am using this particular data format.
Krish NAik: Now, Ashok is asking, is there any good RAG available tools for validation ease? You can use RAGAS, you can use so many. Jess Card is there, Deep Eval is there, Ashok.
Krish NAik: In this course, majorly, we have discussed Ragas.
Krish NAik: Even custom implementations also I have shown you.
Krish NAik: Amit, can you show ENV once? Bolt we need to change to Neo4G? No. If you are working with the cloud instance, then Neo4j. Otherwise, local means, that one. So let me just show you my ENV. Just check.
Krish NAik: Everybody, please tell me that for how many of you the LLM transformer part worked.
Krish NAik: If it worked, then only we can move ahead in the next step. And for how many of you guys cannot make the connection? Then, simply, we will go for a break of 10 minutes, let me look into what is the major issue that you guys are facing. For how many of you, there is a connection issue?
Krish NAik: instance, it's showing new forager, use local, I'm not able to make the connection, Abhishek, Mitesh. Alright, Mitesh, alright. Fine, and let's go, I think, what's the time?
Krish NAik: It's 11, 10, okay?
Krish NAik: Let's look for 5 to 6 minutes, you guys can take a break. I will just look into the issues, and then I will continue from, let's take, like, 11.20, okay? Let's go for a 10-12 minutes break. Alright, just raise your hand, because if the connection doesn't work, then nothing we can do for the other notebooks also.
Krish NAik: So, quickly, raise your hands, I will look into that. So, one is, like, Abhisheikh, Mitesh…
Krish NAik: Rahul is also there.
Krish NAik: So, yes, like, what is the issue that you are feeling, you are having in your local system?
Abhishek: So, it is saying, no connection could be made because Target Machine actively refused it.
Abhishek: It says, please ensure that…
Krish NAik: Show me. Show me, show me.
Abhishek: No possible.
Krish NAik: Because I feel… the issue can be similar. Yes, Raun, in your case also, similar issue?
Rahul Parihar: Mine… no, mine is… I'm able to, establish the old instance connection. I did not create a new one.
Krish NAik: And then I'm… I'm having package issue that.
Rahul Parihar: Langchange underscore NEO4.
Krish NAik: Okay, that package, you have to, you have to do the installation of that, Langchen-new version. That is the name of the package.
Krish NAik: I think it's there, no, in the notebook.
Rahul Parihar: No, no, I… that's what I've run the package.
Krish NAik: Okay, first of all, I think, Bishik, I added you to panelists, start sharing.
Krish NAik: Check, because package-level stuff, I know it might take time, but it will… Ankit is telling…
Rahul Parihar: Good.
Krish NAik: Epoch, Ankit, I showed that epoch solution, no?
Krish NAik: Just click on the cluster, three dots, you will see that plugin options.
Krish NAik: Once you click on plugin, Ankit, you will see Epoch. Just install that automatically. I think your instance will be restarted, Ankit.
Krish NAik: Okay, please, your URL is correct. Okay, I wish it, yes. So, first of all, show me that your, .env.
Krish NAik: Don't use double quotes. Remove all the double quotes.
Abhishek: Okay, good question.
Krish NAik: Where if… Do a command S, restart the condo.
Krish NAik: an environment, but the terminal environment injection, if it's not there, just hard-coded it. That's the other way around.
Abhishek: Okay.
Krish NAik: So just see that after restarting the candle weather.
Krish NAik: Okay, Rajat, alright, just do it.
Krish NAik: Go below, go below.
Krish NAik: Because the target machine is Google, Google.
Krish NAik: Username, show me that, locally it is there or not. Show me locally.
Krish NAik: It's stopped here.
Abhishek: No, no, this is the… Okay, got it. Sorry, yeah.
Krish NAik: Check, man, check, check. Alright, Mitesh, in your case?
Krish NAik: Completely.
Mitesh Shah: of our modeling.
Krish NAik: Yes, but your voice is very low.
Mitesh Shah: Is it better now?
Krish NAik: Yes, better.
Mitesh Shah: Yeah, so basically I'm not able to see the local instance now.
Krish NAik: On the main screen itself, I restarted the New York did extra publication multiple times.
Krish NAik: Like, you cannot see it. Share me, like, if you have deleted it, it will be deleted, otherwise it will be there only, you know, where it will go.
Krish NAik: Nabudith and Shiva? Okay. Could you let me know?
Rahul Parihar: My screen, pawn.
Krish NAik: Okay, okay, I am adding you, okay? Yes, quickly.
Mitesh Shah: Should I start staring, sharing the screen?
Krish NAik: Now, what is a selling could not connect, please ensure that the URL… okay, again, URL issues, guys, you need to look into. Don't use double quotes in your .env, otherwise you're directly hard-coded for your…
Krish NAik: Mean cup to work.
Krish NAik: Because if it cannot pick up… okay, 7687 New Forger, alright, yes.
Krish NAik: Yes, yes, I can… right now, I'm looking into Rahu's screen. Wait, I think, then I will look into Mitesh. Yes.
Rahul Parihar: So, first of all, how do, I just, how do I delete it? I have, the first one, so the delete is disabled here.
Krish NAik: No, no, no, no, you have to first stop the instance, then only you can delete it. There's stop is there? Okay, first stop, then delete.
Rahul Parihar: Okay.
Krish NAik: Methish, you'll start sharing.
Krish NAik: You start, start, parallel, yeah.
Rahul Parihar: I create a new instance, and I connect to this instance, correct?
Krish NAik: Yes.
Krish NAik: Just check quickly, and just pause that, and then… muted.
Krish NAik: Yes. Give a different name, any name, doesn't matter. 1, 2, 3, add something like that, yeah.
Krish NAik: With issues.
Krish NAik: Don't use that at the rate.
Krish NAik: It's a bad practice to use in passwords, you know?
Krish NAik: Sometime it creates an issue, that's why.
Krish NAik: Right. Then, I think you can update your… okay, in your ENV also, pass that password.
Mitesh Shah: Data's already there.
Krish NAik: Okay, if it is there, new 4J, test at the rate 1, 2, 3, the same stuff, alright, go back.
Mitesh Shah: I'm… I just…
Krish NAik: Your error was epoch. Okay, then quickly, I think, yes, install EPOC plugins.
Mitesh Shah: And should I restart the… start it again? That's it, right?
Krish NAik: How it stopped, generally, like, after creation? Okay, start? Yeah.
Krish NAik: Generally, like, automatically it got stopped how?
Krish NAik: This is not running stage, I can see till now it's stopped. That's why.
Krish NAik: It should be… showing they're running under GraphRag 1.
Mitesh Shah: That's what I was trying.
Krish NAik: Right on the phone.
Krish NAik: Because this is the main thing, because without this… Coming stage…
Krish NAik: Okay, just try to create another one. Just create another instance right now, let's see.
Krish NAik: Pass any name?
Krish NAik: Because…
Krish NAik: By default, it's getting stopped, or what, that I could not get in. Why this partial is opening, even I'm not sure.
Mitesh Shah: For everyone, it is opening night.
Mitesh Shah: That's true.
Krish NAik: Pain windows for everybody, alright?
Krish NAik: Install plugin, got it stopped. Okay, alright, let's see, at least, let's wait and see that, it should at least have a running.
Krish NAik: Okay, it now came, I think, after the research had come. Fine, then try to connect with this one.
Krish NAik: 7687 is fine.
Krish NAik: Restart the corner, and, try.
Krish NAik: Start from that, yes.envo, but…
Rahul Parihar: Can I… can I share…
Krish NAik: Yes, yes, you were in panel literature.
Rahul Parihar: So I created a new…
Rahul Parihar: New, new connection, that is test123.
Rahul Parihar: So where I'm supposed to give the database user… that's the username, right? Where do I supposed to give the test?
Krish NAik: No, you don't need to pass.
Krish NAik: through connection URI, it gets recognized.
Rahul Parihar: Okay, so… okay, so with this URI, it should.
Krish NAik: Correct, correct, correct, correct. No issues here.
Rahul Parihar: That won't.
Krish NAik: A new 4G, that will be bold.
Krish NAik: Bolder border.
Rahul Parihar: Right? 768 port.
Krish NAik: Yes, yes.
Rahul Parihar: So when I'm trying to run, this all is getting.
Krish NAik: No, no, no, no, no, no, that you don't know. If you have that, yes, directly execute these two cells. What is the error you are getting shown.
Rahul Parihar: Yeah, this, I'm getting…
Krish NAik: Okay, this package, install it, langchen-neo4j, that is the package.
Krish NAik: It won't be underscored during the package, just install that package.
Rahul Parihar: I, I didn't… Oh, so I just installed this package, right? So…
Krish NAik: Lang.
Krish NAik: hyphen, it's Langchen hyphen, not underscore.
Krish NAik: That is the module, underscore. The name of the package is Langshan hyphen University.
Krish NAik: Okay, yes, I can see the package is available, audited, one package is selling.
Rahul Parihar: So, yeah, that's… this… this package was available.
Krish NAik: do there, and show me then UV pipip show lanchan hyphen NeoForge. Do it in the Jupyter Notebook. Don't do it in the terminal.
Rahul Parihar: So.
Krish NAik: Both the things are different, like, if you do it in Jupyter, in terminal, like, the sync, it takes more time. Do it, everything, do it from the Jupyter, if you want to do any uninstallation.
Krish NAik: Show me, in the Jupyter, quickly.
Krish NAik: Do a PIP show?
Krish NAik: Langchen, yes, I'm telling you only, please create a new cell and write there UB pip show Langchen hyphen neoforegen, the name of the pack. Not… don't do it terminally. Please do it in Jupyter Notebook.
Krish NAik: both the things are different, your terminal environment and your Jupyter environment.
Rahul Parihar: I was always doing it in, terminal, so.
Krish NAik: No, no, no, it actually becomes a problem. Later on, the sync is very slow. Every time you have to do a restart, restart, restart.
Krish NAik: That's why.
Rahul Parihar: And just create a new cell.
Krish NAik: UVPIP show langchen hyphen neoforestj, the same command that you have, just pip show, then it will provide me the confirmation that, in the Jupyter environment, whether it's applicable or not.
Krish NAik: UV pip show, I think you are using UV, yeah.
Krish NAik: Do you believe we've shown the name of the package?
Krish NAik: lanchan hyphen neo4j.
Rahul Parihar: Okay, okay, okay.
Krish NAik: Okay, yeah, so you can directly copy that and just create a new cell in your Jupyter notebook.
Krish NAik: Here, I cannot see… okay, the Langshan Neo4ja package is here. Now, create a new cell in Jupyter Notebook, and just paste that same cell.
Krish NAik: Same command. Then we can get the confirmation that both.
Rahul Parihar: So, how do I invoke the Jupyter Notebook? I have, just for, for, sorry.
Krish NAik: You have opened right now the Jupyter notebook only, no, just create a new cell.
Krish NAik: on top.
Rahul Parihar: Oh, okay, okay, okay.
Krish NAik: Yes, yes, good cell. Click on plus, and now paste that with an exclamatory sign.
Krish NAik: Add that.
Rahul Parihar: Oh, interesting.
Krish NAik: Maybe that UV?
Krish NAik: PIP show. Because from here, then you know that within
Krish NAik: Okay, UV, exclamatory with UV.
Krish NAik: exclamatory with UB pass after it.
Krish NAik: I think lang, L-A-N-G-C-H-N hyphen New Fortune.
Krish NAik: Correct spelling, I think. You can execute that.
Krish NAik: No, no, no, install it, yes, execute, execute, let's see what happens.
Krish NAik: If it shows here, it means that it's there. I think then this package is here. Now, it should import. So, just use that import statement.
Krish NAik: Where it was failing. Go back, yes, go below, below, yes. This input.
Krish NAik: Check once more.
Krish NAik: No module name, it's telling the package is available, the version of the package, just wait, let me see, launch and new for you, what will happen?
Krish NAik: George in the garage.
Krish NAik: 14.
Krish NAik: We waited for you.
Krish NAik: The version is 0.8.0, and I think you are having also the same version.
Krish NAik: Then why it's not getting detected?
Krish NAik: I like it's telling the packages also there.
Rahul Parihar: Did I restart the kernel and try it?
Krish NAik: Try it once, because it's showing that it's available, so…
Krish NAik: Others, like Shiva, you also can let me know your issue.
Krish NAik: Now, there's, I think, Methiche, for you, it worked. Abhishek, you also can let me know it worked for him.
Krish NAik: You are not.
Krish NAik: Shiva, also.
Krish NAik: Worked for me all right. His kernel is selected correct, I feel he is not using .vnv as kernel in the modem.
Krish NAik: No, like, the package is available, at least in that environment.
Krish NAik: Because…
Rahul Parihar: Packages available, right?
Krish NAik: Yes, yes.
Rahul Parihar: circuit.
Krish NAik: No, no, no, no, no, no. Yes, because I can see your Langshan-neo Forager package is available, and that is the main package.
Krish NAik: Langchen-neo4j.
Krish NAik: Just do, in that, cell only, just for a confirmation again, do UVP install, let's see what happens.
Krish NAik: Just do UB paper install, launch a new version.
Krish NAik: Because your version is also the latest one, so it should recognize content now… this?
Rahul Parihar: UVPIP install.
Krish NAik: The same package, Langchen New 4G, yes.
Krish NAik: Just copy that and paste it.
Krish NAik: That is core, not core. Chain hyphen U4J, where you have written ubpip show link chain hyphen u4j.parties.
Krish NAik: Just copy that and paste it, let's see.
Krish NAik: So they're selling audited one package.
Krish NAik: Let's see…
Rahul Parihar: Okay, no…
Krish NAik: Again, execute.
Krish NAik: I was telling that, the first line is only failing land chain underscore Neo4j.
Krish NAik: Well, the package is exactly correct.
Krish NAik: Langchen underscore Neo4j, Neo… okay, okay, NEO4J graph, yes, everything is correct there.
Krish NAik: Last, final thing, open your terminal, the terminal part, leave the notebook now.
Krish NAik: open in, data, write their Python, and hit enter.
Krish NAik: Just copy-paste that import statement and see directly from shell whether it's working or not.
Krish NAik: Because then later on, I will look into that, it's already living.
Krish NAik: 20, okay. So just… just write Python and hit enter, and then, write the import statement there.
Krish NAik: Abhishek is telling I hard-coded, okay, fine.
Krish NAik: Now paste here that import statement, which was not working directly.
Krish NAik: Import statement, yes, either below, below, below, below, below, below, below, below, below.
Krish NAik: Below that… That means…
Rahul Parihar: statement. Can you tell me the statement?
Krish NAik: from Langchain underscore Neo4j input, Neo4j. Oh, okay, okay. This is where your code is failing, no? Yes, copy this and paste it there.
Krish NAik: Wait, wait, here only it feels like…
Krish NAik: Here, it's taking time.
Krish NAik: If it works here, you have some environment issue. Check, because here it's working.
Krish NAik: So some environment issue is there in your system, because terminally, I can say that, yes, it's working fine, okay? So please have a check on that.
Krish NAik: Because it's environmental evolution only.
Rahul Parihar: Alright, it's working after. Alright, so now…
Krish NAik: I will just get back, everyone, just wait.
Krish NAik: They shake, hard-coded, nothing should look at it.
Krish NAik: Fine, now let me just get back here, desktop 3.
Krish NAik: Alright. Now, this is the dataset. Already, I've showed the dataset, this is the movie dataset, okay? So this movie dataset that I'll be loading it.
Krish NAik: Now, I'll be loading it through a variable, which is row. Okay, and the entire data of this particular CSV file, I'll be accessing it through this particular variable, like, row.
Krish NAik: Okay, and then comes the movie ID. So, movie ID is what? The column name. If you see here, somewhere here, your movie ID will come, similarly. It means that through that variable, I'll be accessing all the column names.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, like, your movie ID, director, actor, and everything. And here, I'm using this merge operation. Merge, I told you, like, merge is a safer operation. Every, time. Create, is a little bit, like, risky. Like, what happens?
Krish NAik: In create, it will always try to create, but if something is already existing, okay, then it will throw an error. So we don't want that condition. Merge is a safer condition, where it actually checks that whether it is available or not. If it is not available, then only it will create.
Krish NAik: Yeah, so that's why everywhere you can see merge, merge, merge. So, a better alternative of create is Merge.
Krish NAik: Okay, so for every operation that I have done it, because this entire dataset needs to be fed and create a graph. So, let me just show you the graph here.
Krish NAik: the graph object.
Krish NAik: Alright. Now, this is your mean graph schema.
Krish NAik: Okay, so we can see the graph schema that got created here.
Krish NAik: Okay, so right now I've not pushed it anywhere.
Krish NAik: But, this is my main one. With respect to the main headers that I have done it, I have loaded, merged it, okay? So…
Krish NAik: Now, if I go back here… Just tweet.
Krish NAik: Gosh… Connect to our instance… I will just try to make a connection.
Krish NAik: Can you see here?
Krish NAik: that,
Krish NAik: your, everything, that movie, so, like, Toy Story, Adventure, Tim Allen, everything, that graph that I have done it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so it's available here.
Krish NAik: We can check, so majorly, three main nodes are there, the genre node, the movie one, the person one.
Krish NAik: with respect to relationships, like, acted in, directed in, in genre. That way, it has been created.
Krish NAik: Alright, so similarly, you can do the visualization through the browser as well as through this direct dashboard under the Explore section. Whichever way you feel it, you can do it.
Krish NAik: Okay. Now,
Krish NAik: This, from the package of Langch and Neo4J, you have a direct chain available, called as the Graph Cipher QA chain.
Krish NAik: Because we need to decode, or we need to create the cipher query language. It means that a normal user will pass a query, an English query, just like text to SQL. So here, text to
Krish NAik: Cypher query language.
Krish NAik: Okay, because SQL, CQL, and SQL, I hope you get it, because this is the main task that they are doing.
Krish NAik: So, here, in Markdown, if I write it, it's simply… text, Boo?
Krish NAik: Your CQL. Okay? SQL here means CQL. I hope everybody gets it.
Krish NAik: Now, here, in the chain, what I am passing, first of all, the LLM definition, then the graph that I have created, varpose is equal to true, and allow dangerous request is equal to true. Okay, because if you don't pass this, you might get some type of warnings. Okay, now this is actually a dangerous request, okay, because a lot of calls that needs to be made.
Krish NAik: Now, this chain I have created, now, to this chain directly, I can pass a question, directly pass a query, like, who was the director of the movie GoldenEye, okay? So, this is a rough one that I have passed it.
Krish NAik: So, you can see Martin Campbell, okay? So, Martin Campbell, I will just copy-paste this, and I will show you.
Krish NAik: Here, Ctrl-F.
Krish NAik: Ctrl, V.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here, GoldenEye. This is the movie that came. So, similarly, some other movie also that you can pick up, like, Casino is there. Okay, Casino, let's try to get Casino.
Krish NAik: Yeah, Casino.
Krish NAik: Because, can you see here, match a movie GoldenEye in genre? So, here, Martin was the director. So, based on this, again…
Krish NAik: I can say it… okay, now this is the main one. Now, when you try to look into this one, this is the actual query which has been generated, okay? And on this query, if you try to pass it where?
Krish NAik: I think you will be getting the same results, I hope.
Krish NAik: Local host.
Krish NAik: 7474.
Krish NAik: slash browser… okay, I'm just showing you that original…
Krish NAik: Can you see here? The same one, Martin, that came?
Krish NAik: Okay, so Niher also… The main director.
Krish NAik: Where the name of the director will be there, check.
Krish NAik: Martin… I think, casino is the movie that I picked up.
Krish NAik: Yes, Martin's… that is coming, okay, trauma crime 8.2. So you can have a check based on the query which is generated by the LLM. Okay, so it's pretty much…
Krish NAik: text to SQL, but that's not SQL, it's SQL, Cypher query language. That is the main thing which is doing.
Krish NAik: Where is the dataset.clv? Amit is asking.
Krish NAik: Amid, it's embedded in the Jupyter Notebook cell.
Krish NAik: It is embedded here.
Krish NAik: He can actually execute this entire thing here also.
Krish NAik: So, entire thing, here. So, for example, I'm just showing you, this part. So, here, if you want to do something like a load.
Krish NAik: Can you say load CSV operation here is also there?
Krish NAik: So here also you can do it, or I have done it, through the Langshim package.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: I hope everybody get it, please let me know.
Krish NAik: what we are trying to do. Okay, Rahul is telling, I resolved the environment issues, now I'm not able to connect the GraphDB from import. Try to hardcode for now, okay? Rahul, try to hardcode, otherwise I will come to you.
Krish NAik: Okay, credentials are not correct. Okay, just wait. Try to hardcode, otherwise I will come. Venkatesh, our notebook has written the data to GraphDB.
Krish NAik: Our notebook is writing the data to grab the exactly correct Venkatesh.
Krish NAik: Our mood book is actually, like, first of all, reading the data. See, this is writing the data.
Krish NAik: Writing the data means this operation that I have done. Everybody see this.
Krish NAik: This loading the dataset is there, no. Now, this is where.
Krish NAik: If you try to copy-paste this entire thing, okay, and if you try to paste it here, you can do it, yeah.
Krish NAik: I hope you get it.
Krish NAik: whoever, Vengatesh.
Krish NAik: Once we execute this, it means that everything will be, loaded into your craft database.
Krish NAik: The variable name can be better, yes, for sure it can be better. For now, we are just doing it for this sake.
Krish NAik: So, Ashok is asking, chain.invoke query is equal to how many people has name that starts with Martin? Alright, you tried that one.
Krish NAik: I'm not sure.
Krish NAik: GraphQuery can actually help you to fetch that information.
Krish NAik: But you can try.
Krish NAik: Mubic query result, I don't know. Yes, by default, if something is… really, I don't know the answer, it's a common thing that happens in graph.
Krish NAik: Because in the chain definition, it has been written, because right now, I'm using a pre-chained one.
Krish NAik: So, by default, you might get it.
Krish NAik: It opens some partial while executing, but can't see the logs.
Krish NAik: Generally, like, whenever you are doing any execution in the, history, okay, so for example, like, here, this history, you can get it, not the Python driver history, that you cannot get it.
Krish NAik: Because this is still now something easy that I have done. I've not taken an actual PDF and I have done it.
Krish NAik: In many cases, like, if you ask a very complex question, simply will say that I doesn't know. So it really, like, I don't feel it's up to the mark or something like that. But again, like, generating that particular query
Krish NAik: Because somehow I feel that it's not so much good.
Krish NAik: Because I'm not taking actual document. If I take an actual document, then really you can understand what is happening. This was a simpler example with a CSV file.
Krish NAik: Once this gets executed, please let me know, then we will proceed ahead with the next steps a little bit.
Krish NAik: It opens, okay, Venkatesh, how these implementations work? In production, it's not necessary. If you are taking, really, I will never use these things in production.
Krish NAik: GraphRag is a risky business. It might… because it is such a way structured, if I knew that something fixed the structure of certain documents, then only I will pick it up.
Krish NAik: You have to take a decision that whether you will be taking it into production or not.
Krish NAik: This is R&D, everything from research is not taken into prod, Venkatesh.
Krish NAik: Now, you have to take that decision.
Krish NAik: And even with scalability also, GraphRag has an issue.
Krish NAik: That's not scalable.
Krish NAik: Ravi is asking, are you saying graph rack is not… no, you can use it in production, if your data is not so much big, because at a certain state, if your graph becomes bigger and bigger, it becomes really a problem. Then I never prefer it in production. Some people might prefer it, but simply, like, it's my call
Krish NAik: Personally, I don't prefer.
Krish NAik: If there is no structure in the data, if my data is totally flat, rag, graph rag doesn't make any sense. If you have such type of data where you have some type of linkage.
Krish NAik: Okay, through which you can define entities. Generally, like, contract-based, invoice-based documents, okay, then pharma-based documents. There, there is always a certain standard which is maintained. In those cases, only it is helpful, not in generic, open use cases, I can say. I hope you get that rubbit.
Krish NAik: If there is a structure to your data and which has been standardized, completely, you know that in future also it won't change. It's good.
Krish NAik: If you ask it, and…
Krish NAik: Because I feel that if you have a structure, then actually you can ask to do the verification of the structure. If you don't have a structure, then what to verify?
Krish NAik: So, for GraphRack, this is very, very important. You need to have some type of structure. That's why in CSV, there was a certain structure based on that we followed. Now, in the next step, I'll be taking a PDF. Now, in the PDF, I'll be showing you that again. Like, if I pass something wrong entities, everything will be different.
Krish NAik: Where you have…
Krish NAik: A linked entity is just like, for example, with respect to CSV file that I have shown.
Krish NAik: If it's structured data, why not use text to SQL?
Krish NAik: Why not use the database is only different?
Krish NAik: Text to SQL is a different… this is NoSQL databases, Ravi.
Krish NAik: Both the databases are totally different.
Krish NAik: Not bad.
Krish NAik: Similarly, like, there is another use case for Mongo also, like, because at the end of the day, this is text to NoSQL that we call it in high level.
Krish NAik: Satish, where to show notes relationship in our local Neo4j? Click on that Explore option, under Explore.
Krish NAik: From Explore, you can get it.
Krish NAik: Even, like, I'm not a fan of crap rack, true toothing.
Krish NAik: Because there are a lot of people promoting RapRack, but I am not really, because when I look into the original research paper, the research paper is not following standard, that's all.
Krish NAik: Everything, I feel, it should be standardized.
Krish NAik: So… because even I show you, you guys, whenever you go through the paper, and if I feel that it has not been standardized.
Krish NAik: According to the core metrics of RAG, and they are using everything controlled situation. The entire environment was controlled. They have used their own datasets that they have created. So, for sure, in those environments.
Krish NAik: Their algorithm will win.
Krish NAik: But in real time, it doesn't work. It's just like the Chinese model. Every Chinese model, like GLM, they work for short-term tasks, but over the long horizon task, where they have to run for continuous 20 to 25 minutes, every Chinese model fails.
Krish NAik: They are only GPT-based models, and anthropic models, they really shine.
Krish NAik: That's… that's why that… Man-in-the-middle problem well there.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, Ravi, you're asking what are the improve… you have to actually improve your data set.
Krish NAik: Improve your nodes, improve your relationship.
Krish NAik: It means in data level, you have to actually play the game. In rag level, you cannot do it.
Krish NAik: Your rag will only work if the quality of the data is good.
Krish NAik: I was asking, is there any mathematical or statistical way to identify if my data is more relationship-oriented?
Krish NAik: directly see, because you're… we can take a sample, we can perform a few tests, but again, I won't say that
Krish NAik: Because… because at the last part you write, which is accustomed to vector database.
Krish NAik: Because that part I don't feel, because I can say that, yes, to some level, I can find some relationship with a subset, or a sample of your data, but again, for vector databases, because really, for me, vector databases doesn't matter.
Krish NAik: It's just the algorithm, you have to understand. Whichever, it can be TFI, TF, any type of embedding algorithm.
Krish NAik: Because, yes, I can say it, but again, only for vector databases is not possible.
Krish NAik: It is good for domain-specific data where ontology… yes, correct. Ontology is one of the main things there.
Krish NAik: Yes, Palantir, they have that. Even they are working a very similar tech, like Aadhaar in India, Palantir in the English. That's why their stocks went so much high in the past 2 years.
Krish NAik: Okay, could you please add the Git link of this notebook in Notion? Could you please add the Git link? Alright, I will add that. But, because I have another notebook to discuss. That is the actual notebook. This notebook is for beginner level.
Krish NAik: the advanced notebook that I've created, that I actually need to discuss it today. I think it's 11.13, no? I think we can proceed ahead with the 1142.
Krish NAik: Please let me know, like, because this is a graph.
Krish NAik: This is the actual place where I've taken that PDF implementation.
Krish NAik: Please let me know, can we do it today?
Krish NAik: Yes or no?
Krish NAik: Because I am planning then, tomorrow a little bit about, see, how many of you know about graphite? Anybody have heard about graffiti, real-time knowledge basis?
Krish NAik: Like… Because, changing vector databases is not, such…
Krish NAik: I think, no, no, no, that was this one.
Krish NAik: How many AFI are brought in?
Krish NAik: Graffiti…
Krish NAik: Yeah, something like this, actually, that, I was planning with respect to Falgar. There are, really good things, and you can create, real cases, but again, like, I can change this one. This is the actual link.
Krish NAik: I won't be talking about scalper, because databases is pretty much the same stuff, but I want to talk about this particular approach, like, building real-time. So, how many of you know the concept of temporal rag?
Krish NAik: Anybody has heard temporal rag? So, generally, in temporal rag, we use graffiti.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: If somebody has used temporal, so then…
Krish NAik: Same thing, very similar things, but actually in real time, like, based on timestamps and date, you can do a lot of filter-based operation, okay? So tomorrow, then, I'll be talking about this one. So you can see a temporal knowledge, graph architecture. Okay, the actual paper is there.
Krish NAik: Little, because of the graph rack.
Krish NAik: Again, but I feel that this is much more somewhere valuable around.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I'll be talking about this tomorrow, then Zep AI.
Krish NAik: Because, again, these are all nasally researched. Now, it's not necessary that everything is used in production.
Krish NAik: Yeah, it's another one, because from here, the mean concept of temporal rack came into the picture. That's why I thought about… we will discuss about this.
Krish NAik: But before discussing this, let's start with… This one, because…
Krish NAik: Here, also, you have a very similar configuration, and if you, really look into this piece of code, I feel that it's easy, it's not hard.
Krish NAik: Okay, but yes, a custom relationship that needs to be defined. So, here, if you really look into this one.
Krish NAik: Okay, so just focus here, everybody. Okay, so leave, whatever the trials that you are doing. I want you guys to focus on this part.
Krish NAik: So here, when I was creating… okay, so just check this. I didn't pass any custom rules, so exactly what are the rules that needs to be followed? It's pretty much blank implementation.
Krish NAik: Now, here, what I have done… I have passed what type of nodes that needs to be created, and what type of relationship that needs to be created.
Krish NAik: Now, you have this particular option to pass it to your LLM graph transformers.
Krish NAik: One is… that is, okay, everything, LLM will figure it out, but you can at least pass few of the major entities that you feel which are required for your node creation and for your relationship creation.
Krish NAik: Because here, I've, my PDF document is just like the last time, I think, that environment document, which I have, but here I've added these rules.
Krish NAik: Similarly, if you have a different one, I think this is another example where you can allow, like, allowed nodes and allowed relationship. It means that you can create your custom entities and you can pass it.
Krish NAik: So that the LLM actually knows that, okay, these are the nodes and the entities that, nodes and the relationship that needs to be created.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's it. This is where I made something custom rather than quarterly, like, depending on the LLM. Can anybody tell me what is the benefit of doing this?
Krish NAik: What will be the benefit of doing this?
Krish NAik: Less hallucinations… Structured, yes. If I pass this, I know that these are the rules.
Krish NAik: And outside these rules, nothing will be followed.
Krish NAik: That is the best thing. So, whenever you are working, so I will always suggest
Krish NAik: keep your nodes and relationship to a certain… it's not like, You should make it open-ended.
Krish NAik: Because if the type of document changes, and if you don't pass any type of rules, again.
Krish NAik: Like, unnecessary nodes and relationships will be created.
Krish NAik: Based on that document. So, really, like, not a good practice. So that's why I'm showing you, you should always decide, at least look and analyze your data, at least a sample of your data, and then decide what should be the nodes and what should be the relationships.
Krish NAik: So let me know, should I discuss this notebook tomorrow?
Krish NAik: Because then tomorrow, this notebook, and with the other implementation of a temporal rack that we'll be discussing. Because this is actually a hybrid implementation in Neo 4G. If I show you, see, this is a vector index, the same thing that we have done previously.
Krish NAik: Okay, because in Neo4j, it has the support for grab databases as well as vector databases. I think,
Krish NAik: In 2024, they brought the feature of vector embeddings also. So that's why that feature is there. So what we need to do?
Krish NAik: We need to create that hybrid
Krish NAik: I hope everybody gets, we need to create some type of hybrid retrieval. One is your original retrieval, and the other one… okay, so here, what I have done…
Krish NAik: I have created a custom one, so a custom retriever that I have created, which is called as Ensemble Retriever. I think everybody remembers Ensemble Retriever in Llama Index, we have done the implementation, but not in LanChain.
Krish NAik: Where we are actually combining both the retrievers, and then we are giving weightage. 60% weightage to our graph, and 40% to our vector.
Krish NAik: Pretty much, it's like… Our sparse and dense, if you think about.
Krish NAik: So, if you have your time, please go through, otherwise tomorrow I'll be doing the discussion. Yes, that's why this is hybrid rack. Dense plus graph.
Krish NAik: Two things that I've taken, you can add more and more stuff. You can add sparse also here, you can add multi-vector also here, you can make the pipeline much more robust.
Krish NAik: Okay? So this is another option. So this is the same thing, and I think little bit of land graph that I have taken just for conditional routing.
Krish NAik: Okay, so tomorrow I think we'll be talking about these things then.
Krish NAik: I don't already.
Krish NAik: Now, people with problems, raise your hand, I will look what is the problem that you are facing.
Krish NAik: Rahul, okay. Others, for everybody, everything is working, because tomorrow's session will be a little bit, like, out of the syllabus. In your main syllabus, temporal rack discussions is not there, neither, real-time knowledge bases is there, so just a new added thing.
Krish NAik: And I think then from next week, we'll start a little bit of haystack and multimodal stuff.
Krish NAik: It's working, let's take it today. I know what others are telling, no.
Krish NAik: Generally, when Mudasar says stop, then I continue on Twitter. Mundasar is only telling continue. I am stopping.
Krish NAik: We fetch the notes from VectorTV and get more details. Yes, that is the IT.
Krish NAik: Obviously, because it's, see, it's a very similar operation if you think about, like, in Project 2, we have not done a hybrid approach, but there, we have not taken a, that, particular… if you remember, there was a mode of booth in Project 2.
Krish NAik: Okay, that mode is a very similar approach here, that hybrid one. Vector plus graph approach.
Krish NAik: Raul, I think if you can start sharing, I'm adding you to panelists.
Rahul Parihar: So there are.
Rahul Parihar: Vote.
Krish NAik: Okay, Ashok, alright, Ashok Grazier, and I need to look into that.
Rahul Parihar: Yeah, yeah.
Krish NAik: Because if the LLM is generating correct, cipher query language, so it should.
Rahul Parihar: Nope.
Rahul Parihar: So, Paul, you can see.
Krish NAik: GSA has pretty much done people who want, they can drop. I will just look into the issues right now. Because there can be certain issues.
Krish NAik: Yes.
Rahul Parihar: So I… I'm… I created a new…
Rahul Parihar: instance. This is the username. This is what the pass… this is what the user data looks like.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Rahul Parihar: Okay.
Rahul Parihar: And then, I hard-coded it also, sent it, it says no, no…
Krish NAik: Show me, show me, show me, show me your instance running that part, show me once.
Krish NAik: This is running 7687.
Krish NAik: Oh, one door… Turben 001, this is fine.
Krish NAik: Okay, here I can see everything is fine.
Krish NAik: Okay, go back to that, pi once.
Krish NAik: And.
Rahul Parihar: is environment file.
Krish NAik: Board, localhost… 7687… and there also, it was 7687 only, not the port.
Krish NAik: Because only I'm worried about the port.
Rahul Parihar: 7687, yeah.
Krish NAik: 127, same stuff, like… write 127.00 only, then. Exactly. Don't write localhost.
Krish NAik: Generally, it both is the same stuff it should work with.
Krish NAik: Santosh and Ashok, just wait, I will unmute you guys.
Krish NAik: Just try, because, there is nothing… anything else, Graph TV123, I don't think any…
Rahul Parihar: Okay, so…
Rahul Parihar: I wanted to talk about… that's okay, I'll figure that out. I wanted to talk about one parking lot for…
Rahul Parihar: this AWS infrastructure, I'm thinking of doing a POC in my company with all the documents that are very information-specific, they are getting stored. So, remember one of the complex projects of text-to-SQL project that we have done it?
Rahul Parihar: So does that…
Rahul Parihar: project, I'm trying to connect that with, an LLM, but I want the guardrails, and the security mechanism in such a way that, firstly, what information is getting
Rahul Parihar: asked to LLM.
Rahul Parihar: and what informations are getting stored. So, the project requires some of the legacy, you know, files.
Rahul Parihar: that those are, like, mainframe files, you know, getting converted, because Cloud came out with COBOL, you know, conversion code, you know? So some of the…
Rahul Parihar: Yeah, some of the very complex tasks that is undoable right now is converting job 1 to… of a job to a COBOL, you know, pseudocode, you know, for that.
Rahul Parihar: So, if the… if I have a flat file, I upload it into a vector database, and ask
Rahul Parihar: the… the same text-to-SQL program saying that now CURI, based on the input files that you have received, create a context to a LLM to ask
Rahul Parihar: To generate some of the output files.
Rahul Parihar: So, how will this project, you know.
Rahul Parihar: So, how will this whole mechanism, will that work? You know, first of all, the pilot project that we did for Text2SQL in this context. And this is an architecture which is converting everything
Rahul Parihar: everything, from an open source to more, more AWS-oriented, you know, for example, Titan M.
Krish NAik: It's just cloud-native, but…
Krish NAik: not cloud-agnostic things that we do. This is fine, like, there is no issue, but, really, like, the type of the data and how things are there, because this loading, chunking, this is the main part. Like, the data that you'll be processing, and, like, I can see your self-hosting quadrant.
Krish NAik: So, that is also fine, but exactly, like, how? Because,
Krish NAik: It totally depends upon that chunking and loader part. You have to take the decision by doing some experiments.
Krish NAik: Because that is the main thing. If you try to solve, you have to spend most of the time in that part.
Krish NAik: Because the rest of the architecture, I can say that, yes, because.
Rahul Parihar: Yeah.
Krish NAik: that… how to deal with the data. Because the rest of the things are fine, because these are hard-coded algorithms and certain services that will be connecting. But the actual research will come into that data parsing and this one.
Krish NAik: Because, really, even I cannot directly say. You have to analyze your data, and then you have to take that, at least a subset of your mean data, and you have to test it out.
Krish NAik: That, weather is working, Because in high level, it looks correct, the architecture that you have done.
Rahul Parihar: Okay. So, on a high level, So, but…
Rahul Parihar: if I'm using Cloud, Sonata 4.6, you know, API calls, those calls, those are capable of… because it's a… it's a task that's been, so you're saying, basically, chunking of that data is going to be
Rahul Parihar: Pretty, niche, right?
Rahul Parihar: Storing those jobs into a vector database, into a sequence, that will be able to chunk it, right? Basically, what I'm not able to get it is exact, you know, chunking size and overlap size that the.
Krish NAik: No, no, no. Here, you have to use from anthropic only. One concept came up, context retrieval.
Krish NAik: Okay, like, in every chunk, keep some information. It means that based on your query, I prefer that way. You can look into, they have. Even I will teach it in your coming classes as an extra class. So generally, like, in every chunk, try to keep a question.
Krish NAik: That this chunk is about what?
Krish NAik: Okay, in that way, it becomes… your search becomes much better, I feel. Okay, without having any context, just because of that, because most of the time, people ask questions.
Krish NAik: Okay, that question-to-question match is always better, I feel. Okay, so that… a simple concept in anthropic there is called as that, and the other thing is prompt catching.
Krish NAik: Again, cloud model supports and GPT models, not every model, but if you are working with Anthropic, not an issue. Both the things comes.
Krish NAik: So, there actually, you can, through prompt catching, I know that your context size, won't be getting bigger and bigger.
Krish NAik: That is one of the added benefits, so you will have pretty much a space left out, like, 1 million context window, so easily you can handle it. So these two things you have to take care of on top of that particular research.
Krish NAik: That you were doing.
Rahul Parihar: Okay, okay.
Rahul Parihar: Can you throw me some con… Some documentation on anthropy?
Krish NAik: Yes, yes, yes, see. It's famous only, it's not like it's 2024. Even I will teach that I have the content with me, but, just…
Rahul Parihar: But anyone in the group has done AWS, similar text-to-SQL… Text-to-SQL is…
Rahul Parihar: is one of the main program and the complex program that we have done as a project, right? Which makes a lot of sense.
Rahul Parihar: Correct? The multirag one.
Krish NAik: That's a good point.
Rahul Parihar: Keith.
Rahul Parihar: So, over there, you have, we have kind of done, caching.
Rahul Parihar: implementation, as well as, SQL query generation, you know?
Krish NAik: There are actually… you can actually train it also. In VANA, there is a… like, I have not shown you, I was planning to show, you can actually train, like, by providing some golden examples. Like, according to your dataset, at least, if you can provide 100, 200 examples, the…
Krish NAik: output becomes much better. Okay, now this is exactly… can you see, like, this is the one? I'm sharing it in the chat. Even in class, I will be discussing, I think.
Krish NAik: after 10th or 12th March, but this is really, like, it's really good for handling longer prompt, prompt catching.
Rahul Parihar: Are you sharing something?
Krish NAik: I think which screen I am sharing the…
Rahul Parihar: Okay, desktop 3, I think, yes.
Krish NAik: This is introducing contextual retrieval. This is old stuff, 2024 only, but I have shared the link in the chat. You can open this and you can explore, because for generally rag-based tasks, it's, widely used, but again, prompt catching is not…
Krish NAik: Supported by everyone. Not every LLM. Majorly, in 2026, I can say GLM models, min-max models, Anthropic and… are working, you won't have any type of problems. And Anthropic content is there, so you can look into this, so this is really a good one in optimizing a lot of stuff.
Krish NAik: it actually helpful.
Krish NAik: Okay, so keep it bookmarked, and you can explore it, and you can add it. Because the rest of the stuff, like Heidi and those things are, again, plug-and-play module. If you feel that you are not getting the result, you can actually test those things out. But at every point of time, I don't feel it's required. This is one…
Krish NAik: Okay, so… yes, so… Now, this is a little bit expensive, but always understand, because this context plus chunk, context plus chunk, context plus chunk.
Krish NAik: Okay, so little bit, but again, if you have the LLM, you don't need to…
Rahul Parihar: VANA is going to be, again, open source within AWS.
Krish NAik: with the reply.
Rahul Parihar: basement of one now.
Krish NAik: No, no, you have to host it, just like that. You can host here. That is open source, but you can host VANA into the custom, like, anything to just host it. I think it will be better.
Krish NAik: Because recreating that, because nobody in the market, I will say, has such a robust
Krish NAik: One. Neither Langchain, neither… because, LanChain, never use it. Llama Index, you can at least play with…
Krish NAik: There, you have the SQL table retriever, at least it's better than the Langchen one, I can say. But finally, like, VANA is, like, the golden standard. You know, for most of the POCs that I suggest to any clients, I have seen the results are better from VANA.
Rahul Parihar: Okay, then VANA will be used for basically indexing and… Properly chunking it, right?
Krish NAik: Not for indexing and chunking, that will be your main one.
Krish NAik: If you have a SQL validator, there, in those cases, it's not required. There, you need to actually pass that context schema. Now, how optimized that you can through, and with that, concept of training through multiple golden examples.
Krish NAik: For your documents, it will come. By… for your SQL data, you will be using that.
Rahul Parihar: Got it, got it. So, VANA would definitely would be the one which will.
Krish NAik: Define the more…
Rahul Parihar: the link.
Krish NAik: You can host it in your own, I think that will be better, just like… but I will suggest, okay, like, if you'll be using it a lot, then only do it in a pod inside EKS. Otherwise, go for EC2, if you have lesser calls to make it.
Rahul Parihar: If you have a lesser call to make it. Okay, let me try that route, and I'll throw some questions and some architectural questions to you on the email, Paul.
Rahul Parihar: Yeah.
Krish NAik: Thanks. Ashuk, as I was telling, alright, I figured it out. Other Santosh? Kantush?
Santosh Umargi: Yeah, Paul, yeah, thank you for, today's, class. Actually, Paul, I have one, means, like, problem statement in company for the regarding classification and LP tasks. Like, it is,
Santosh Umargi: like, one event, creation task, no, it is there. So, like, suppose a user has inputted, there is fire.
Santosh Umargi: And, then the LLM will, identifies the category. So, we have, we have created a POC, like, suppose he, inputs the fire, then it is, category will be fire, and then subcategory will be medical emergency, like that.
Santosh Umargi: So, so from the evaluation perspective, how the flow should be for this classification task?
Krish NAik: You have to create your own synthetics, because you have to create your own eval data set. In every NLP problem, or AgBest everywhere, for LLMs also.
Krish NAik: Now, you need a synthetic data generator. According to your use case, at least start with 50, 60, because generally what I do, I keep on increasing my evaluation dataset through inferencing.
Krish NAik: more people inference, I do the validation, I add it into my data set. That's the general… general flow. But, at least start with few examples, at least skip. Like, what is the size of the data? At least take 7-8% of that.
Krish NAik: Okay, in your eval, so 10%, I think it wouldn't be good. But you have to create that manually.
Krish NAik: You can use the rules, like, through RAGAS also, you can create, through, like, deep evil also, you can do synthetic data generation. This is done by many libraries.
Santosh Umargi: Okay. So, and, how in production this evaluation, means flow will be like that? Like.
Krish NAik: See, in production, initially you will start with a small one, and later on it will be inferencing, you know, when people will be doing it.
Krish NAik: So generally, what happens, we keep a feedback button, something like a hands-up, or even in ChatGPT, in any type of conversational-based system, you can keep some type of feedback. If somebody is adding it as a positive feedback, you can automatically add it in the evaluation.
Krish NAik: And even you can put that same stuff in Cache also, because that is validated by some user.
Santosh Umargi: Okay. Okay, okay, I got it.
Krish NAik: In that way, I generally handle it, I keep it in both the places. If somebody is going, I know that it becomes actually a golden example. Now, on top of that, I have seen, like, some people suggest, like, even do the validation of it once.
Krish NAik: Because some people might come and just hit that buttons.
Krish NAik: Okay, that's why. Because you have to do that implementation according to your skills. If you see lesser number of people, that is the best way. You create your own subset, then keep on adding it through your real inference.
Krish NAik: That's how… then through that, you can actually manage model drift also.
Santosh Umargi: Okay, okay.
Santosh Umargi: Yeah, okay, thank you, Bolia, got it.
Krish NAik: Hari is asking, looking for system, technical, like, system design development by…
Krish NAik: I don't have that, generally I prefer books, that I…
Krish NAik: hurry, like, I already told, like, Chipman ML system design, that is, like.
Krish NAik: the Bible for machine learning guys that I figured.
Krish NAik: And right now, I can say the Indian market is hiring dangerously, I think, for the past one month. People want to make a switch start.
Krish NAik: Because people are offering good salaries. Many organizations in Bandu
Krish NAik: It's just, like, people who are planning to switch.
Krish NAik: start.
Krish NAik: Because, like, 100%, 150% hikes, many organizations are…
Krish NAik: mainly in Belanor, I can say that Belandur area, many organ… more than 50, It's,
Krish NAik: organization I've heard, last 10 months, and more than
Krish NAik: 20 to 30 folks have made the switch in the last 2 weeks.
Krish NAik: Everybody, like… And usually, they have got good offers.
Krish NAik: Okay, so try to make that, because right now I feel that this is the time when you can make a lot of money.
Krish NAik: people, if you feel that you are having lesser package, try to make a switch. Because this time, really, like, people who won't…
Krish NAik: People who are not adopting AI, now it has become a necessity.
Krish NAik: So… Start giving interviews, don't wait for a long time.
Krish NAik: And at least the content that I have taught, I know that is really…
Krish NAik: Cracking, I feel, that 25 to 30 lakhs package is very easy. For that 50 to 60 lakhs package for principal data scientist, a few other things need to be discussed. Probably in my next course, I'll be taking that stuff.
Krish NAik: Okay, but at least for RAG level, I think by the end of this course, you guys will be, like, close to 70-80% of major RAG stuff. Now, according to your part, start creating POC, because when you take something to scale, even I don't know, like, what will happen in your system. It becomes an incremental learning.
Krish NAik: You have to spend 8 to 9 months, actually, to do a certain level of optimization.
Krish NAik: Yes, for architect role, a few other things are there.
Krish NAik: Productionizing, and again, research, two things are a bit different. My, take on good. That cloud one, yes, I am planning, because skills is right now, even helpful for me. Also, I was using skills.
Krish NAik: For, that, automating certain content generation tools, actually, for me also. It's good, I will talk about that cloud code, don't worry. I will take that session.
Krish NAik: Architect, for now, I will say stick to one cloud, be good in one cloud.
Krish NAik: Okay, because if you're good in one cloud, then majorly, like, most of the questions on architect level.
Krish NAik: are from, like, cloud perspective, I feel. They are asking why this technique, why this technique?
Krish NAik: A lot of questions that were asked to me.
Krish NAik: Because, again, but the architect level, few other things that needs to be known, and I feel that LLM prospect, we need to focus a lot.
Krish NAik: People, like, how many of you have not fine-tuned it? Simple, simple models.
Krish NAik: We will be a little bit working on that. But this project form that I have released, everybody please do fill up.
Krish NAik: Okay, it's important, that's why I've shared with you. Again, I'm sharing. Please take your time, I think, where I shared this one, okay? So here is the entire plan, okay, and at least 30 people.
Krish NAik: Because for them, for the next batch also, I will plan something, okay? So, I've already shared this form, so please do, like, 26 people, because I will do the filtration with another colleague of mine.
Krish NAik: Okay, so again, I'm sharing.
Krish NAik: just be sure in whichever cloud. I need good cloud, guys, because this is completely cloud-native part.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: like, if lead 3 is required, I can make it small changes, but
Krish NAik: be sure that, at least. You're spending some time, I think within 2 months, easily, you can do it.
Krish NAik: That's why, like, start using AI. If you… at least I will say, for this project, use AI, okay? The cheapest model in the market that you can work with is GLM. GLM or Kimi, they are really good. Like, probably in those Chinese models, what happens, in a single iteration, you might not
Krish NAik: be getting the perfect. So, one iteration, 2 iterations, three iterations, I can say by 4th or 5th, you will be getting.
Krish NAik: Whereas in Cloud Code, within one iteration, in Codex one iteration, you get the perfect result.
Krish NAik: Okay, so if you have… everything is configured.
Krish NAik: So that's why, please, I can say.
Krish NAik: participate in this, this will be 2 months, like, your batch will be completed, then also there's project meetings I'll be taking.
Krish NAik: Okay, so weekly one meeting or something like that. I feel that in your… if you are going even for your interviews, this project will be pretty much helpful. So, spend some time, at least, that's why I'm telling 5 hours weekly, if you can give it. Using AI 5 hours is a huge deal.
Krish NAik: without using AI sidebars, then I can say that, okay, but using AI, it's a huge deal. So, participants spend some time, even from my side, I will try to put, okay.
Krish NAik: See, I can put time in AWS and GCP, but Azure guys, whoever is doing, just be sure you are good, because they are really, like, I am…
Krish NAik: I use very specific services only from Azure, so I'm not good in Azure, so I'm telling you beforehand only. AWS and GCP, I can't do it.
Krish NAik: Text-to-sql project, others are there, but not also. Like, VANA is the standard that I've taken.
Krish NAik: Okay, people who are good, like Sanali and others, you guys can let me know. Future of coding, like, see, like…
Krish NAik: People are telling after 6 to 8 months, a lot of things will be automated, but let's see. Whatever happens in US and India, it takes…
Krish NAik: More than one year to 2 years to come, the actual after-effect.
Krish NAik: I don't feel. Right now, the hiring has increased. Certain things will be there, which will be automated.
Krish NAik: And I feel most of the things which are repetitive tasks. With respect to R&D, and everybody, I will suggest, stick to R&D, because my plan is, at least for the next 6 months, will be sticking to R&D. People who are in R&D will always be safe.
Krish NAik: very, very safe place. That's why I focus, like, okay, fine, you are good in cloud, but at least be in some part of R&D.
Krish NAik: That's my next close will be highly a frontier AI research-type batch that I'm planning, actually.
Krish NAik: a lot of… everywhere in RAG also, how to bring reinforcement learning, those things I will keep. Everywhere, reinforce learning, I will try to add it.
Krish NAik: Because that is the next level, research solution.
Krish NAik: very less productionized happens, but a lot of research is there. And probably, I feel that in future, those things will be adapted.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that is the plan. So everybody, please do fill it up. Again, tomorrow I will share, and by next, week, then let's see, actually, okay? Because I have to spend some time and do the filtration, then the final group and everything, I will, release it.
Krish NAik: Because I can see 39% people using Claude.
Krish NAik: So, I can say Codex… Codex, really? Like, GPT 5.3, people don't love it, or what?
Krish NAik: Okay, or I feel that, okay, cursor and this one is 21%, fine.
Krish NAik: You use through these tools.
Krish NAik: Amanda.
Santosh Umargi: Codex used through Copilot.
Krish NAik: I got it, got it. That's why, you guys are… because, see, my idea was that everything through command line.
Krish NAik: No ID. That's the practice right now.
Krish NAik: Okay, fine, it will be an interesting, a lot of other things that will come.
Krish NAik: Because, she used stuff… Perfect.
Krish NAik: Alright, so tomorrow's discussion, again, I'm repeating, I'll be discussing the notebook. You guys can go through in the meantime. Then I'll be talking about temporal rack, where I'll be talking with respect to gravity, and let me see that if I can take Falker or ArangoDB, that was the another one which is famous.
Krish NAik: Whichever I can take, so probably two implementations that are available.
Krish NAik: And then I think next week, let's see, because next week, I think I can start with haystack, or probably multimodal, right?
Krish NAik: In multimodal RAG, you need good GPUs.
Krish NAik: That's why, like, docklings with grenade support, even, like, Minor U,
Krish NAik: Or NEMO PARS, that's why next week we will be taking that decision. So, little bit of research you guys can do, and if you have time, please go through the paper of Nemo Pars.
Krish NAik: Okay, Nemo Pars… Paper.
Krish NAik: How many of you know about Nemo Pass?
Krish NAik: Mmm, paper.
Krish NAik: Anybody have heard?
Krish NAik: No, no, it's Nemopars, not Memopos.
Krish NAik: Maybe if you have an invisible.
Krish NAik: Box.
Krish NAik: This is actually an OCR, yes.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, like, this is… I feel that, this is a really good.
Krish NAik: Okay, and in this paper, a lot of others, like Monkey OCR, Hunan OCR… okay, a lot of Chinese OCRs are also there, which is really good, GLM-based OCR.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, which one to pick up? Because I will pick up the IBM Doppling, which has become a standard. Other… a lot of things are there till now, that you know that in every multimodal, the first thing is layout understanding. Now, for layout understanding, so two separate models.
Krish NAik: a pipeline that needs to be done. Okay, and minor view is another favorite, but again, Chinese stuff, very less people will be willing to
Krish NAik: actually do the implementation in their local. Okay, this is really good stuff, but you need a lot of RAM, like 20GB of VRAM.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… this is my personal favorite, but again, complexity is very… So, that's why next week, let me plan, I will just create a list, and then let's see what to do in multimodal 1.
Krish NAik: Because a proper document parsing pipeline, I feel that we should do it.
Krish NAik: Alright, fine. Okay, Viraj is telling, Viraj, AWS RAC platform, I've already started working. Okay, Viraj, in the meantime, just be part of the group, and in the meantime, you can start working, okay? Let me see, like,
Krish NAik: CCC, whenever you are doing any implementation, no, Alec.
Krish NAik: even if I look into your commits, it becomes very hard for me. See, guys, whenever you are making, like, anything, create different branches.
Krish NAik: Okay, because then it becomes easier to track and achieve the commits.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, it becomes very, very hard for me. If it's a Jupyter notebook, it's a different thing. But at least if it's a code space, try to keep it in certain level, that this is feature, this is feature, this is feature.
Krish NAik: Okay, later on, like, if you try to explain that project to your POs, it becomes much easier. Okay, so I'll be talking about those strategies also. Work tree, very, very important. Okay, if you are working with Claude, now it supports directly. Otherwise, start creating separate branches and keep your work.
Krish NAik: Alright, so don't worry, so let's see by next week. Let's meet tomorrow, and then we'll be talking about what themes for interview questions will you suggest? Majorly, like, Santosh, interview questions, if you want directly, let me know, because RAG questions right now in industry, it's really questions.
Krish NAik: Little bit of research, you say, and most of the people are getting hired based on research stuff.
Krish NAik: In Indian market. Little bit of DSA, then good packages are coming.
Krish NAik: presume. All right.
Krish NAik: I think few people, one got into Atlassian, or TAM,
Krish NAik: one in that Israeli company is there. Few people got it. Okay, let me ask for their resume. Okay, and then I think by next week. Okay, drop me a meal with respect to that.
Krish NAik: Because that,
Krish NAik: It's a little bit, like, personal level, so whoever is there, drop me a meal, I have to ask, and then I can do it.
Krish NAik: Alright guys, so I think I will stop sharing. Okay, let's meet tomorrow. Rave's asking, sorry, what is the project form? Go through that form, the… all the document is there, read the document. It's not like I've created a blank form. If you have this, you will see that
Krish NAik: In this form, you have this one, like.
Krish NAik: like, AWS native, this is something like that you will be building.
Krish NAik: And this is the estimated plan, so just go through that everything, Rev.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why every… because this plan is there, I'll be creating Discord groups and others.
Krish NAik: But once the final selection is done, then only.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's fine.
Krish NAik: Baldrit.
Krish NAik: All right, guys, so let's, conclude it for today. Let's meet tomorrow, and we will continue our discussion. Okay, so bye-bye, everyone. Thanks for joining.